serve
仕える
Academia Sinica's dramatic speech
中央研究院の劇的なスピーチ
Colleagues in this hospital, guests outside the hospital, hello everyone
院内の同僚、院外のお客様、皆さんこんにちは。
This new year begins this year
今年も新たな一年が始まります
We are very happy to invite Professor Zhong Yuan from the Department of Chemistry, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学化学科のZhong Yuan教授をお招きできることを大変嬉しく思います
Come give this month's intellectual feast
今月の知的な饗宴にぜひお越しください
A certain professor has known him for 46 years
ある教授とは46年来の付き合いだ
In 1966, many people were still unborn
1966年にはまだ多くの人が生まれていませんでした
In 1966, we were freshmen in the Chemistry Department of National Taiwan University.
1966年、私たちは国立台湾大学化学科の新入生でした。
train together for success
成功に向けて一緒にトレーニングする
At the same time we are classmates
同時に私たちはクラスメイトでもあります
We all went to America in 1971
1971年に私たちは皆アメリカに行きました
Get Washington University
ワシントン大学を取得する
Ph.D. in St. Louis
セントルイスで博士号を取得
Then after postdoctoral
その後ポスドクを経て
play me two years back to Taiwan
2年前に台湾に戻って遊んで
Started his teaching position in Taiwan in 1978
1978年に台湾で教職に就く
By now everyone knows
もう誰もが知っている
He's been switching fields along the way
彼は途中で分野を変えてきた
been converting
変換している
I didn't do experiments by hand before.
私はこれまで手作業で実験をしたことがありませんでした。
He started with theoretical statistics
彼は理論統計から始めました
Then do the energy conversion later
後でエネルギー変換を実行します
these experiments start experimenting with
これらの実験は実験を開始します
Then his field is very wide
それから彼のフィールドは非常に広いです
we have all in this scene
このシーンにはすべてがある
Structure of Liquid Water from Statistics
統計から見る液体の水の構造
mesoporous molecular plug
メソポーラス分子プラグ
and its application
とその応用
There is also Feijun Xiangchumei
フェイジュン・シャンチュメイもいる
nanomaterials
ナノマテリアル
for biomedical applications
生物医学用途向け
and biological conditions
および生物学的条件
So his field started from the physical chemistry group of the early chemistry department
彼の分野は初期化学部の物理化学グループから始まったということですね
From the present inorganic group to the present chemical biochemical group
現在の無機グループから現在の化学生化学グループへ
he stayed
他都待過
Ask him to teach some organic words
彼にいくつかの自然な言葉を教えてもらう
He becomes the domain of all chemistry departments
彼はすべての化学科の管轄となる
I don't think it's a waste of his time
彼の時間の無駄だとは思わない
Then everyone applauds and welcomes this report.
そうすれば誰もがこの報告を拍手で歓迎します
Thank you Xumin for the introduction
シュミンさん、ご紹介ありがとうございます
good night listeners
おやすみリスナーの皆さん
I wish you all a happy new year here
ここで皆さんに新年明けましておめでとうございます
still during the new year
まだ新年中
I think a lot of people haven't really gotten into the working situation yet
まだ実際に仕事に慣れていない人も多いと思います
Well, when I entertained the Chinese New Year earlier, I was at home a few days ago.
さて、数日前に旧正月を楽しんだとき、私は家にいました。
then come out to play
それから遊びに来てください
Come out and play later, right?
後で遊びに来てね？
Then we are very happy to see so many friends here tonight
それでは、今夜ここにたくさんの友達に会えてとてもうれしいです
this feast
このごちそう
good food
いい食べ物
this
これ
This is actually a small piece of research I did
これは実際に私が行った小さな研究です
but as a public speaker he is more popular
しかし演説者としては彼のほうが人気がある
Well, I'm here too and I'm not going to give my personal speech.
さて、私もここにいますが、個人的なスピーチをするつもりはありません。
Just to talk about some thoughts on this subject
この件に関していくつかの考えをお話したいと思います
Then these thoughts may be helpful to some young friends
そうすれば、これらの考えは若い友人たちにとって役立つかもしれません
maybe it's okay
たぶん大丈夫
at least see if there is any entertainment value
少なくともエンターテイメント性があるかどうかを確認してください
nano-bionic materials
ナノバイオニクス材料
Let’s talk about bionics first, bionics means to imitate some mechanisms of living things
まずバイオニクスについて話しましょう。バイオニクスとは、生物のメカニズムを模倣することを意味します。
and its related this material
およびそれに関連するこの資料
Unavoidable means that I imitate from a very small degree
やむを得ないというのは、ごくわずかな範囲から模倣することを意味します
Materials for human development are a long way off
人類開発のための材料はまだまだ遠い
From this period, the Iron Age, to the present IC, what are these?
この時代、鉄器時代から現在の IC まで、これは何ですか?
This development of a material
今回の素材開発は
The recent materials all emphasize being smart and smart
最近の資料はどれもスマートでスマートであることを強調しています
Biology gives us a good reference point
生物学は私たちに良い参照点を与えてくれる
In fact, the scientist or engineer first started teaching this method
実際、最初にこの方法を教え始めたのは科学者または技術者でした。
This man is famous
この人は有名です
I think it's doing this
これをやっていると思います
the ancestors of this matter
この件の先祖たち
ah
ああ
this
これ
what is this
これは何ですか
he said this
彼はこう言いました
it should be possible
それは可能なはずです
this
これ
you are point
あなたがポイントです
you want to move forward
前進したいですか
This is point
ここがポイントです
I'm going down now
今から降ります
the second one
2番目のもの
he didn't pay
彼は支払わなかった
first pay one
まず1つ支払います
ok
Ok
ah
ああ
Da Vinci
ダ・ヴィンチ
If in the future this line
将来この行があれば
to have a greatest award
最高の賞を受賞するために
Shouldn't be a Nobel Prize
ノーベル賞にあるべきではない
Should be the Grand Vinci Award
グラン・ヴィンチ賞を受賞すべき
first want
最初に欲しい
mimic creature
生き物を模倣する
make a
作る
Deed built
証書が完成しました
We can say that the earliest bionic
最も初期のバイオニックと言えます。
biomimetic design is
バイオミメティックデザインは
this great this big Vinci
この素晴らしい、この大きなヴィンチ
this is his manuscript
これは彼の原稿です
he
他
in the box
箱の中
this is an aircraft
これは飛行機です
flying is a human
飛ぶのは人間だ
this dream
この夢
I want to be human for the people
人々のための人間でありたい
people just want to fly
人々はただ飛びたいだけなのです
That
それか
In China, old Taoists used to tie this rocket to a chair and sit on it
中国では、昔の道教信者がこのロケットを椅子に縛り付けて座っていました。
fly up
飛び上がる
then fell to death
その後転落死した
Now you also watch some extreme sports
これでエクストリーム スポーツも観戦できます
All want to satisfy this desire
誰もがこの欲求を満たしたいと思っています
Da Vinci
ダ・ヴィンチ
he
他
At once
すぐに
design a flying machine
飛行機械を設計する
You can easily tell at a glance that he is imitating a bird
鳥の真似をしているのが一目で分かります
the flight of the bird
鳥の飛行
Of course at that time it was a matter of motivation
もちろん当時はモチベーションの問題だった
no source of power
力の源がない
He can't make a plane
彼は飛行機を作ることができない
Immediately following the human desire to fly is not
人間の空を飛びたいという欲求はすぐには起こらない
First use this aircraft
まずはこの機体を使用
da vinci's flying machine satisfies
ダ・ヴィンチの飛行機械は満足する
but this
しかしこれは
balloon
バルーン
This is the first time a human has gone to space
人類が宇宙に行ったのはこれが初めてです
In this Paris in 1783
1783年のこのパリで
Avenue of Xiangxiao
香暁大道
very large audience
非常に多くの聴衆
The so-called big science at that time
当時のいわゆるビッグサイエンス
is this science
これは科学ですか
and ticket
そしてチケット
No need to apply to Congress for this research grant
この研究助成金を議会に申請する必要はありません
I charge tickets
チケットを請求します
received tickets
受け取ったチケット
You can earn money to support your own research
自分の研究をサポートするためにお金を稼ぐことができます
At that time, one of the famous participants was Charlie
当時の有名な参加者の一人がチャーリーでした
charlie is a physicist
チャーリーは物理学者です
one thing he's famous for is
彼が有名なことの一つは
Study the temperature at which this volume is proportional to
この体積が次の値に比例する温度を調べてください。
absolute temperature
絶対温度
But I'll mention it later
でもそれについては後で言及します
He actually wasn't Charlie the first to go up into space.
実は最初に宇宙に行ったのはチャーリーではありませんでした。
the first to lead to charlie with a relative's ascension
親戚の昇天でチャーリーに最初につながった人
this is the same year
これは同じ年です
1783 than he played
彼がプレーした1783年より
This hot air balloon went up and played for months
この熱気球は上昇して何ヶ月も遊んでいました
At that time it was a ban
当時は禁止だった
patients, so there are many ordinary people who are willing to pay to support scientific research
患者なので、科学研究を支援するために喜んでお金を払う一般人がたくさんいます
it's okay
それは大丈夫
clear balloon
透明な風船
this is carmontisi
これはカルモンティシです
According to Camontisi this electrolyzed water yields clear research
カモンティシによれば、この電解水は明確な研究結果をもたらします。
So that's all the best research of our time.
つまり、これは私たちの時代で最高の研究です
It's a pity that the biological science research list was not so popular at that time
生物科学の研究リストが当時あまり普及していなかったことが残念です
At that time it was physical chemistry
当時は物理化学だった
Relatively speaking, hot air balloons are more lively
比較的熱気球のほうが活気がある
Because you're filling a hot air balloon for an afternoon
午後は熱気球に荷物を詰めるから
Wait about half an afternoon.
午後半日ほど待ちます。
Everyone can see it and go up
誰もがそれを見て登ることができます
The clear ball needs to be electrolyzed for a month
クリアボールは1ヶ月間電気分解する必要があります
After one month of electrolysis, the balloon is still clear enough
1 か月の電気分解後でも、バルーンはまだ十分に透明です
But what follows is still not a bionic story
しかし、その後に続くのはまだバイオニックの物語ではありません
still a balloon
まだ風船
By the 19th century balloon travel actually became a romantic affair
19 世紀までに、気球旅行は実際にロマンチックな行事になりました
A lot of people are fine, spend money on a balloon
多くの人は元気で、風船にお金を使います
No, buy this ticket and get on the balloon
いいえ、このチケットを買って気球に乗りましょう
Go to this other trip to play
この他の旅行に遊びに行ってください
In the 24th period, even develop this
24期ではさらにこれを発展させて
This big letter balloon that slaughtered 1,000 people
1000人を虐殺したこの大きな文字風船
It's this balloon that travels across the Atlantic Ocean
大西洋を渡るのはこの気球です
this is the restaurant inside
ここが中のレストランです
Can do more than 1000 people, very big
1000人以上が参加できる、とても大きい
Of course it was a big disaster in the end
もちろん結果的には大惨事になったけど
When this new insurance number lands
この新しい保険番号が到着したら
stormy then out to this telecommunications and then
嵐はそれからこの通信に行き、そして
sunny day
晴れた日
If I think about it now, if I was appalled at the time
今思えば、あの時愕然としていたら
This balloon flight may have broken down less suddenly.
この気球飛行は突然故障することはなかったかもしれない。
It means to say one thing
それは一つのことを言うということです
Something that doesn't necessarily regenerate is useful
必ずしも再生しないものは役に立つ
At least in Da Vinci's time at that time, the beauty was different
少なくともダ・ヴィンチのあの頃は美しさが違った
It's beautiful, from an engineering point of view.
エンジニアリングの観点から見ても美しいです。
is a beautiful design
美しいデザインです
but it doesn't use
しかしそれは使いません
what you want to achieve you have other ways
達成したいことは他にも方法がある
so i'll start with this
だからこれから始めます
that means not to say
それは言わないことを意味します
Anyway, it can solve your current slight problem
とにかく、それはあなたの現在の小さな問題を解決することができます
But the problem with this flight
しかし、このフライトの問題は
Of course, it's back to peeing in the end.
もちろん最後はおしっこに戻ります。
Airliner Boeing Design We Are Doing Now
私たちが現在取り組んでいる旅客機ボーイングの設計
this
これ
basically from a bird's house
基本的に鳥の家から
It was Da Vinci's idea
ダ・ヴィンチのアイデアだった
coming
到来
But the nearest plane
でも一番近い飛行機は
you noticed
あなたは気づいた
There are many further floors
さらに多くのフロアがあります
you didn't notice the current plane
あなたは現在の飛行機に気づきませんでした
The wings and tails of many airplanes are raised
多くの飛行機の翼と尾翼が上がっています
It is imitated the wings of this eagle
この鷲の翼を模したものです
There is this cock to make the air flow
空気の流れを作るためにこのコックがあります
Generates more stable airflow
より安定した気流を生成します
fly more stable
より安定して飛ぶ
I remember airplanes from decades ago not being like this
何十年も前の飛行機はこんな風ではなかったのを覚えています
Now there is an artificial intelligence
今は人工知能がある
But this is imitation big
しかし、これは大きな模造品です
not what i'm talking about today
今日私が話している内容ではありません
But let's start with this to illustrate a
しかし、これを説明するためにこれから始めましょう
Even imitating the effects that living things can achieve
生き物の効果を真似しても
One of the most important dreams of mankind
人類の最も重要な夢の一つ
on the aircraft to complete
飛行機内で完了する
Next, let's take a look at what the biology itself has
次に、生物学自体が何を持っているかを見てみましょう
are we worth noticing
私たちは注目する価値がありますか
and then go a step further to imitate
そしてさらに一歩進んで模倣します
These are some of the nanostructures in nature that I'll show you first
これらは、最初にお見せする自然界のナノ構造の一部です
And now scientists will want to mimic its
そして今、科学者たちはその手法を真似したいと思うでしょう。
The first one is this butterfly wing
1枚目はこの蝶の羽です
the butterfly wings
蝶の羽
it has colorful things
カラフルなものがあります
this is a variety of colors
これは色々な色があります
But it is not made of pigment
ただし顔料でできているわけではありません
Usually we make the color of a thing
通常、私たちは物の色を作ります
I draw a watercolor
水彩画を描きます
This variety of colors is due to different pigments
このさまざまな色の違いは顔料の違いによるものです
direct this
これを指示する
The absorption light pattern is different due to the
吸収光のパターンは次のように異なります。
It's not that it has a so-called optical crystal structure
いわゆる光学的な結晶構造を持っているわけではありません
periodic structure
周期構造
after the light shines on
光が当たった後
produced this
これを作った
an interference phenomenon
干渉現象
produced
生産された
It's like a gas leak on the road
路上でガス漏れしてるみたいだ
a thin layer of gasoline you will see the color
ガソリンの薄い層で色がわかります
Then the structure of
次に、の構造
of
の
periodic size
周期的なサイズ
When changing it has
変更すると、
different colors
異なる色
In this case
この場合
For a deep point its design is simple
奥深い割にデザインはシンプル
It only needs to adjust the color slightly
色を少し調整するだけです
It's the same Motive
それは同じ動機です
continue with the same design
同じデザインを継続する
no need to go
行く必要はありません
produce many different
たくさんの異なるものを生み出す
pigment
顔料
chemical production
化学製品の製造
It's good energy we all know
それは誰もが知っている良いエネルギーです
The energy of chemical functions is the same in living organisms
化学作用のエネルギーは生物でも同じです
You have to do all kinds of different compounds
あらゆる種類の異なる化合物を実行する必要があります
that is energy consuming
それはエネルギーを消費します
it doesn't need to be
そうである必要はない
Also of course the famous history
もちろん有名な歴史も
Many people have heard of this
これについては多くの人が聞いたことがあるでしょう
this lotus
この蓮
The water drop on the lotus
蓮の上の水滴
is easy to roll
転がりやすい
it can use this to collect water
これを使って水を集めることができます
Then pour this droplet into a lotus midsole
次に、この液滴をロータスのミッドソールに注ぎます
Although it's not raining
雨は降っていないのに
But it is carefully
でも慎重にね
To have collected water droplets method
水滴を集める方法
method can collect this liquid
この液体を収集できる方法
There are many structures on this
これには多くの構造があります
Almost Zhou Qixing
ほぼ周啓興
but don't need this
でもこれは必要ありません
But many fine bumps
でも細かい凹凸が多い
The so-called lotus effect
いわゆるロータス効果
Of course we'll make sense of it
もちろん意味はわかります
If you go a step further, now this is a goose
もう一歩進めば、これはガチョウです
For geese, its central structure can be designed
ガチョウの場合、その中心構造は設計可能です
very detailed
非常に詳しい
So that the goose can have different colors when its wings are closed and when they are opened
ガチョウの羽が閉じているときと開いているときで異なる色になるように
And because the wings can be adjusted as they move
翼は動きに合わせて調整できるので、
Let's talk about it
では、それについて話しましょう
grains, just light
穀物、ほんの軽い
Organisms use this inescapable structure to control light
生物はこの避けられない構造を利用して光を制御します
the control particle
コントロール粒子
this spider silk
この蜘蛛の糸
Spider silk is very strong and tough
クモの糸はとても強くて丈夫です
very strong
非常強
You've all heard this
皆さんも聞いたことがあるでしょう
In terms of units
単位に関しては
Its strength is stronger than steel
鋼鉄よりも強いです
In addition, special mention
その他、特記事項
It absorbs vibration energy very well
振動エネルギーを非常によく吸収します
It's the wind that blows
吹くのは風だ
It doesn't say it's vibrating very hard
それほど激しく振動しているわけではありません
just break
ただ休憩するだけ
It absorbs vibrational energy
振動エネルギーを吸収します
It is of course a single row structure
もちろん単列構造です
The structure of single-row mass can be very strong
単列塊の構造は非常に強力です
and elastic
そして弾力性のある
is our man-made fiber
当社の人造繊維です
Said that it is not yet so good
まだそこまで良くないって言ってた
we have strong
私たちには強い力がある
Like the mud dragon is very strong
マッドドラゴンはとても強いようです
But the flexibility is not as good as
しかし、柔軟性はそれほど良くありません
absorb this vibrational energy
この振動エネルギーを吸収します
not as good as
就比不上
Another letter
別の手紙
This is a marine oil creature
これは海洋油生物です
I am not a student of biology
私は生物学の学生ではありません
I don't know much either
私もあまり知りません
what is its chinese name
中国名は何ですか
It has a row of tiny magnets inside its creature
生き物の中に小さな磁石が並んでいます
This is raising Huashan iron
これは華山鉄を育てています
it can
できる
and line it up
そして並べてみる
This is for relative geology
これは相対地質学用です
sense of direction
方向感覚
it sense of direction
それは方向感覚
The place it needs to live is in the water
生きるために必要な場所は水の中です
This place where the concentration of breeding is relatively high
比較的繁殖密度が高いこの場所
The geological nature of that layer
その層の地質学的性質
very different
とても違う
It can use this as a sensor
これをセンサーとして使えます
If you add an additional layer
さらにレイヤーを追加する場合
If you hold a magnet against it
磁石を当ててみると
it will line up against this magnet
この磁石に向かって整列します
This it can control the magnetism
これで磁力をコントロールできる
we are in the lab
私たちは研究室にいます
little baffling little events like this
このようなちょっと不可解な小さな出来事
easy to make
作りやすい
Recent experiments in our laboratory
私たちの研究室での最近の実験
development can not do
開発はできない
but
しかし
we can't make it yet
私たちはまだそれができません
just let it line up
ただ並べてください
and it's just that long
そしてそれはちょうどそれだけ長いです
not too long
長すぎません
just line up so long
こんなに長く並ぶだけ
we can't do it yet
私たちはまだそれができません
So you can do a lot in this
これでたくさんのことができるようになります
And to achieve its special function
そしてその特別な機能を達成するために
other words
他の言葉
some of them
それらのいくつか
We don't really know about this feature
この機能についてはよくわかりません
but it is very beautiful
でもとても美しいです
It's that simple
それはとても簡単です
it can be done very beautifully
とても綺麗に出来ますよ
This is the microalgae called plankton in the bottom of the sea
これは海底のプランクトンと呼ばれる微細藻類です
There are tens of thousands of species of algae
藻類は何万種も存在する
all the water in the world
世界中のすべての水
Both freshwater and seawater have
淡水も海水も
it is a single celled organism
それは単細胞生物です
Its main structure is the dioxide system
その主な構造は二酸化物系です
Another series of things it is calcium carbonate
もうひとつのシリーズは炭酸カルシウムです
all beautiful
すべて美しい
When the structure of this it is like that
これの構造だとこんな感じ
The one in the Forbidden City
紫禁城にあるもの
What is that called Jiulongshu?
それは九龍酒というものですか？
many layers
多くの層
all have holes
どれも穴がある
that's a typical
それは典型的なものです
In this case, its full gene has been solved
この場合、その完全な遺伝子は解決されています
know the structure of this gene
この遺伝子の構造を知っています
it looks like two pieces of that
それは2枚のようです
The pins are hooked together
ピン同士が引っ掛かっている
There is a belt in the middle
真ん中にベルトがあります
Different slender it's all beautiful
違う細い、それは美しいです
but looks different
でも見た目が違う
You can classify it by its appearance
見た目で分類できる
Inside is a single cell
中には単細胞が入っている
so
それで
of course we know
もちろん私たちは知っています
Its main function is to protect
その主な機能は保護することです
that is
あれは
It's hard, isn't it?
大変ですね。
Then the hole can pass oxygen
そうすれば穴は酸素を通すことができます
But we really don't know why it grows so beautiful
しかし、なぜこれほど美しく成長するのかは本当にわかりません
this is also
これもまた
this
これ
confused one
迷惑之一
In addition
加えて
in the lab
研究所で
draw a family today
今日は家族の絵を描く
Dioxide systems can be easily made
二酸化物系は簡単に作ることができる
Porous carbon dioxide system can be made
多孔質二酸化炭素システムが作製可能
but absolutely can't do it
でも絶対にできない
we are far away from this
私たちはここから遠く離れています
We can't make such a beautiful thing
私たちにはそんな美しいものは作れない
don't know how it's made
どうやって作られているのか分かりません
do not know either
どちらも知りません
don't know
わかりません
know a little bit
少し知っています
this is a creature
これは生き物です
some of some material
いくつかの資料の一部
brief introduction
簡単な紹介
when you start
始めるとき
Know that he can do many things
彼は多くのことができることを知ってください
to meet the needs of his life
彼の人生のニーズを満たすために
In addition
加えて
We are all familiar with Google
私たちは皆 Google に精通しています
this
これ
There are many properties in biological materials that are
生物材料には多くの特性があります。
it
それ
yes
はい
not heart
心ではない
it is hollow
それは空洞です
Then what
じゃあ何
It has a so-called layered structure
いわゆる階層構造になっています
this is not shown
これは表示されていません
here
ここ
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
this
これ
Google puts Aratu in your stomach, you can see it
Google がアラトゥをお腹に入れたらわかりますね
it's light
軽いです
especially bird
特に鳥
very light bone
とても軽い骨
but
しかし
It can support a strong force
強い力を支えることができる
this weight
この重さ
it's the most important thing
それが最も重要なことです
there will be
あるだろう
so-called layered results
いわゆる階層化された結果
Let me explain this first
まずこれを説明しましょう
must use this opportunity to say
この機会を利用して言わなければなりません
Explain what is a layered result
階層化された結果とは何かを説明する
behind us
私たちの後ろに
meeting
ミーティング
talked about
話しました
It's a bone about a centimeter in size
1センチくらいの骨です
and you start zooming out
そしてズームアウトを開始します
The seventh stage of the shrinking company has a unique structure in each size
縮小する会社の第7ステージは規模ごとに独自の構造を持っています
Let's start with the smallest skeleton, which is divided into two parts
2 つの部分に分かれている最小のスケルトンから始めましょう
Inorganic and Organic
無機と有機
The non-deposit is basically this spiritual acid calcium
非沈殿物は基本的にこの霊的な酸カルシウムです
Calcium Spiritate with Oxygen Clearing
酸素除去効果のあるスピリテートカルシウム
It's the little thing in the middle of the drawing here
ここの絵の真ん中にある小さなものです
And then another strong protein like muscle protein
そして、筋肉タンパク質のような別の強力なタンパク質
called Collagen
コラーゲンと呼ばれる
it is arranged like this
このように配置されています
This is the word in the smallest size
これは最小サイズの単語です
There are probably tens of nanometers to several nanometers here
おそらくここには数十ナノメートルから数ナノメートルがあるでしょう
Then
それから
Color Gyn stacks up here
カラージンはここに積み上げられています
Then discharge a structure in a very orderly manner
次に、非常に整然とした方法で構造を放電します。
This is the protein structure
これがタンパク質の構造です
is one of the so-called triple helixes
いわゆる三重らせんの一つです
Because of this triple helix it's a very strong protein
この三重らせんのおかげで、それは非常に強力なタンパク質です
Then what
じゃあ何
further words
さらに言葉を
it forms this fiber
それはこの繊維を形成します
This fiber has a gradation from small size to large size
この繊維は小さいサイズから大きいサイズまでグラデーションになっています
to the fiber
繊維に
That is where you put this small piece or this piece
そこにこの小さな部分やこの部分を置くのです
Immediately, where to put this small piece or this piece
すぐに、この小さなピースとこのピースをどこに置くか
Take this small piece where to put it or this piece
この小さな部分をどこに置くか、この部分を持って行きます
You keep looking this way until you get to the big size
大きなサイズになるまでずっとこちらを見続ける
Go all the way here to the small size
Sサイズはここまでどうぞ
its different sizes
さまざまなサイズ
To adjust and make such a complex structure
このような複雑な構造を調整して作るには
We usually build, look at a building
私たちは普段、建物を建てたり、建物を見たりしています
Building a building like 101 is complicated enough
101のような建物を建てるのは非常に複雑です
but
しかし
basically
基本上
If from the room to the floor to the whole building
お部屋からフロア、建物全体までなら
just such a change
まさにそのような変化
and quite monotonous
そしてかなり単調
This is a very complex structure
これは非常に複雑な構造です
Of course we can't do it in the lab.
もちろん研究室ではできません。
we don't know much
私たちはあまり知りません
The whole body of this bone
この骨の全身
What is going on in the physical and chemical process
物理的および化学的プロセスで何が起こっているのか
Then let’s talk about why Nano
それでは、なぜナノなのかについて話しましょう
Why Nano
なぜナノなのか
From the few examples just mentioned
先ほど挙げたいくつかの例から
you can tell
教えてもいいよ
Nano is its bottom foundation
Nano はその最下部の基盤です
The bottom foundation builds up
底の基礎が積み重なっていきます
build this
これを構築します
This hierarchical structure
この階層構造は
the bottom of this foundation
この基礎の底
when going to ride out
車で出かけるとき
The thing at the bottom can be changed again
一番下にあるものは再度変更できます
It can be operated differently
別の操作も可能です
but not the same as above
しかし上記と同じではありません
It keeps this pretty consistent
これはかなり一貫性を保っています
Many of our things are buildings
私たちの物の多くは建物です
If we build it like this
このように構築すると
I started pumping some bricks
レンガを汲み上げ始めました
You can smoke a few bricks
いくつかのレンガを吸うことができます
You can't do it if you smoke too much
吸いすぎるとダメだよ
those bricks are going to fall
それらのレンガは落ちてしまうだろう
but
しかし
Its bricks can still change
そのレンガはまだ変化する可能性があります
What about the second one?
2番目のものはどうですか？
it is autonomous brick
それは自律型レンガです
not like we build a house
私たちが家を建てるのとは違います
we have workers
私たちには労働者がいます
there are architects
建築家がいる
Architects are drawing blueprints to design good
建築家は良いデザインをするために青写真を描いています
In the future, workers will build according to this blueprint
将来的には、作業員はこの設計図に従って建築することになります。
so there is outside
だから外にある
these people come in and do this
この人たちが入ってきてこれをやります
no problem
問題ない
it is to self-assemble
それは自分で組み立てることです
So it needs to start with nano cities
だからナノシティから始める必要がある
go up and assemble
上がって集合する
there's no way you can get chunks of stuff
塊を手に入れることはできない
Will fly around and self-assemble
飛び回って自己集合します
Only small enough things of course
もちろん十分な小さなものだけです
it has brownian motion
ブラウン運動を持っています
These Brownian motions go
これらのブラウン運動は
movement to assemble
集合する動き
organic matter, inorganic matter
有機物、無機物
Single pendulum planting, carbonic acid cover what
単振り子植栽、炭酸が何をカバーするか
it can do
それはできる
to assemble
組み立てるため
In addition
加えて
a physics student
物理学の学生
What everyone likes to talk about is the nature of the so-called world view
みんなが話したがるのは、いわゆる世界観の性質について
at a mesoscale
メソスケールで
When going from nanometers to the scales in between
ナノメートルからその中間のスケールに移行するとき
it's different
違います
Nami's heart
ナミの心
it's not golden
それは金色ではありません
it can be purple can be blue
紫にもなるし青にもなる
when it was at that nanoscale
それがナノスケールだったとき
look different
異なって見えます
when the organism goes
生物が行くとき
When using this nanoscale to do things
このナノスケールを使って物事を行うとき
It equals some more degrees of freedom
それはより自由度が高いことに相当します
It's not just 100 elements
単なる 100 個の要素ではありません
it is equal to many other
それは他の多くのものと同等です
Like the color of the butterfly wings I just mentioned
さっき言った蝶の羽の色のように
it is made of the same material
それは同じ素材でできています
Then in the mesoscale the arrangement is not the same
そして、中規模では配置は同じではありません
its color can vary
その色は異なる場合があります
So these are the things it needs to understand at the nanoscale
これらはナノスケールで理解する必要があることです
to understand the reasons for its results
その結果の理由を理解する
Then I can't go deep
それでは深くは行けない
because that's what it is
それがそういうものだから
Talking about what needs to be studied in depth
深く研究する必要があることについて話す
I can't be in this person today
今日はこの人の中にいられない
just tell you
ただ教えてください
That is to say, what does this concatenated structure do?
つまり、この連結構造は何をするのでしょうか?
In fact, in the butt that kind of thing
実はお尻にはそういうことがあるのです
I can't make it
うまくいかない
because no one knows
誰も知らないから
But there are some things we can imitate to do these
しかし、これらを行うために真似できることがいくつかあります
we can't talk today
今日は話せません
The next thing I'm going to talk about is saying
次にお話しすることは、
we bionic words
私たちバイオニックワード
what to do
何をすべきか
Of course I can use examples one by one
もちろん、例を 1 つずつ使用することもできます
explain
説明
Anyway, I can make a strong pull by doing this.
こうすることでとにかく強い引きが出せます。
this elastic material
この弾力のある素材
There are optical properties when we do it
それを行うと光学的特性が発生します
but i'm not going to talk
でも話すつもりはない
i'm going to ask a question
質問します
These questions are like Da Vinci's original
これらの質問はダ・ヴィンチのオリジナルのようです
raised a human dream
人類の夢を育てた
a big problem
大問題
In fact, after this big problem
実はこの大きな問題の後、
let's see what's there
そこに何があるのか​​見てみましょう
We can do it with bionic technology
バイオニックテクノロジーでそれができる
This is perhaps an important contemporary question
これはおそらく現代の重要な問いです
It's a matter of energy
それはエネルギーの問題です
right now we
今、私たちは
energy problem
エネルギー問題
I'm looking for new energy
新しいエネルギーを探しています
And find the right energy and it needs to be green energy
そして適切なエネルギーを見つけてください、それはグリーンエネルギーである必要があります
What most of us know about green energy is
グリーンエネルギーについて私たちのほとんどが知っていることは、
I don't want to burn that oil coal
石油石炭を燃やしたくない
no nuclear energy
核エネルギーはありません
Then the rest is solar
じゃあ残りは太陽光発電
or use this
またはこれを使用してください
Solar energy produces that hydrogen in hydrogen generation
水素生成では太陽エネルギーがその水素を生成します
Combustion batteries and so on, these so-called green
燃焼電池など、いわゆるグリーン
But I feel that everything is not green enough now
でも、今はすべてが十分に緑ではないように感じます
The original meaning was that you just agreed to say that I will not use these petrochemical energies.
本来の意味は、私がこれらの石油化学エネルギーを使用しないと言うことに同意したということです。
But your design doesn't have any biological principles in it
しかし、あなたのデザインには生物学的原理は含まれていません
so start talking about us
だから私たちのことについて話し始めてください
Now let's think about this
では、これについて考えてみましょう
Just like when Darwin thought about how to fly
ダーウィンが飛ぶ方法を考えたときのように
This is a big issue we face
これは私たちが直面している大きな問題です
It may take decades for us to do this subject well.
このテーマをうまくやるには何十年もかかるかもしれません。
What I mean is to say it well, I really did it, and in the end it was really green
よく言いたいのは、本当にやりきった、そして最終的には本当に緑だったということです
is the highest efficiency
最高の効率です
To achieve the economic efficiency that biology can achieve
生物学が達成できる経済効率を達成するために
Let's look at solar cells first
まずは太陽電池について見ていきましょう
Solar cells I'm talking about solar chemical cells
太陽電池 私は太陽化学電池について話しています。
not that one
それじゃない
Originally made with this Xijing
元々はこの西京で作られていました
that
それか
of course now
もちろん今
We usually buy it in foreign countries
普段は海外で購入しています
buy a solar panel
ソーラーパネルを買う
or something
か何か
Just use Siri
Siriを使うだけ
what we are saying now is
私たちが今言っているのは
like attorney ye
あなたは弁護士のように
but it can be converted into chemical energy
しかしそれは化学エネルギーに変換することができます
or converted into electrical energy
または電気エネルギーに変換される
then you have sunshine
それならあなたには太陽があります
sunlight coming in
日光が入ってくる
later you have
後であなたは持っています
booster here
ここのブースター
Then you have the anode
それから陽極ができます
then you have this
それならこれがあります
cathode
陰極
anode for reaction
反応用陽極
splits water into oxygen
水を酸素に分解する
The reaction at the cathode produces hydrogen
カソードでの反応により水素が生成される
Then simultaneously generate current
そして同時に電流を発生させます
Of course you can adjust
もちろん調整も可能です
Can make this a little less current a little more
これをもう少し電流を少なくすることができます
No need to click a button, it will directly produce new oxygen
ボタンをクリックする必要はなく、新しい酸素を直接生成します。
use it
これを使って
wait but this
待って、でもこれ
One is from the sun
一つは太陽から来たもの
Now of course many people are doing this problem
もちろん今では多くの人がこの問題に取り組んでいます
Then maybe there are a lot of refugee designs in it
そうすると難民のデザインもたくさんあるかもしれない
like this is a refugee design
これは難民のデザインのようだ
this
これ
But let's think about something like this
しかし、次のようなことを考えてみましょう
we need to control many things
私たちは多くのことをコントロールする必要があります
we need to control the light
私たちは光を制御する必要がある
We want to control the current
電流をコントロールしたい
we want to control the gas
ガスをコントロールしたい
it has gas coming out
ガスが出てきています
or fuel electrons when I'm gas going in
ガスが入ってくるときは電子を燃料にする
gas run
ガスラン
gas in and out
ガスの出入り
These organisms are
これらの生物は、
all do this
みんなこれをする
you a fast running newspaper
あなたは速く走る新聞です
It is a very large energy consumption
非常に大きなエネルギー消費です
it sucks in that
それは最悪だ
Oxygen instant air is a lot
酸素瞬間空気が多い
how does it manage
どうやって管理しているのですか
why is that management
なぜその経営なのか
This gas when it is divided into every body in its entirety
このガスがすべての体に分割されると、その全体が
every cell
すべての細胞
integrate it into the cell
それを細胞に組み込む
fastest way
最速の方法
Can be labeled as a great power
大国としてレッテルを貼ることができる
How to do
実行する方法
In addition, the fuel cell
また、燃料電池は、
For example, what I just did
たとえば、私がたった今やったこと
I made blue silver oxygen
ブルーシルバーオキシジェンを作りました
blue silver oxygen delivery
青銀の酸素供給
Then go to other drug areas to use wide
その後、他のドラッグエリアに行き、広範囲に使用します
Or do it by generating electricity
あるいは発電してやる
fuel cell
燃料電池
Here is a simple fuel cell schematic
これは簡単な燃料電池の回路図です
It is to let green react with oxygen
緑を酸素と反応させることです
in two motors
2つのモーターで
electrolyte in the middle
真ん中に電解質
Electrolyte is going straight
電解液は直進します
Then this is of course very environmentally friendly
もちろん、これは非常に環境に優しいものです
because you are water
あなたは水だから
you have no pollution
あなたには汚染がありません
You didn't produce filth
あなたは汚物を生み出しませんでした
carbon dioxide
二酸化炭素
Thanks
ありがとう
OK
OK
This digging diagram is too simplified
この掘削図は​​簡略化されすぎています
You are your student
あなたはあなたの生徒です
The first time you give it to me, you will say this
初めて私にそれを与えたとき、あなたはこう言うでしょう
But that's what I just said about a newspaper going fast
でもそれが、新聞のスピードが速いということについて私が今言ったことなのです
It's definitely not that simple for the gas to come in
ガスが入ってくるのは決して簡単ではありません
Just to do an experiment in our high school
私たちの高校で実験をするためだけに
make a board
ボードを作る
Blow it onto that board
そのボードに吹き付けてください
that doesn't have much power
それはあまり力がありません
Because the surface area is too small
表面積が小さすぎるので
another this
もう一つこれ
Oxygen here is also oxygen
ここの酸素も酸素です
And what about this pointing
そして、この指摘はどうでしょうか
Traditionally, these are the problems you have to manage
従来、これらは管理する必要がある問題です
Your problem with the flow of this object
このオブジェクトのフローに関する問題
if we put it
それを置いたら
If you take a closer look
もっと詳しく見てみると
You need a lot of area here
ここには広い面積が必要です
What about this area?
この地域はどうでしょうか？
makes it easy for hydrogen to walk
水素が歩きやすくなる
like the lungs of a newspaper
新聞の肺のように
you want to be able to walk to
歩いて行けるようになりたい
All Blowing Agents Above
上記のすべての発泡剤
electrons are then produced
その後電子が生成される
soon again on this conductor
すぐにまたこの指揮者で
to run
走る
run out tell me to get out
なくなりました、出て行けと言ってください
other side
向こう側
So, therefore, it's the oxygen side that does the reaction
つまり、反応を行うのは酸素側です
Also like this
こんなのも
Another important point is to have a blowing agent
もう一つ重要な点は発泡剤があることです
Modern working blowers are generally made of platinum
現代の作業用送風機は通常プラチナで作られています
Incredible Platinum Particles
信じられないほどのプラチナ粒子
So in response to a Platinum conduction
プラチナ伝導に応じて
When the time is generated, run from this electrolysis value to the opposite side
時間が発生したら、この電解値から反対側まで走ります
other electronic words
他の電子単語
Very close to a conductor
指揮者と非常に近い
usually carbon
通常カーボン
porous carbon
多孔質カーボン
ok , you just imagine this one question
OK、この質問を想像してみてください
like a living organism
まるで生き物のように
You have to manage the gas and your liquid
ガスと液体を管理する必要がある
How about the fastest exchange to flow
最速の交換フローはどうですか
blown
吹き飛ばされた
Here we immediately see one thing
ここですぐにわかることが 1 つあります
We know that if we really want to make the electrons of the sun
本当に太陽の電子を作りたいなら、私たちはそれを知っています。
Don't do that, it's platinum
そんなことしないでください、それはプラチナです
platinum is expensive
プラチナは高価です
And there are not many platinum reserves in the world
そして世界にはプラチナの埋蔵量はそれほど多くありません
Where are you going to make this electronic
これをどこで電子化するつもりですか
Probably only for one country, the United States
おそらく米国一国だけでしょう
no one else
他に誰もいない
We obviously have to find other
明らかに他のものを見つけなければなりません
Then we have to ask whether there is anything in the organism
次に、生物の中に何かがあるかどうかを尋ねなければなりません
can do something like
のようなことができます
so this imitation
それでこの模倣
From the comparative physics of this fluid
この流体の比較物理学から
How to exchange gas and liquid
気液交換
We have a structure to catalyze
私たちは触媒となる構造を持っています
that in chemistry
化学のそれ
so-called biochemistry
いわゆる生化学
how do you tie this thing together
これをどうやって結びつけるのですか
become an integrated organism
統合された有機体になる
then i pose this question
それから私はこの質問をします
let's see what you're going to manage
あなたが何を管理するのか見てみましょう
What kind of experience do you have in managing this process
このプロセスの管理に関してどのような経験がありますか
biomimetic approach to do
バイオミメティックなアプローチ
efficient and cheap
効率的で安い
Let's not wait for these with platinum
プラチナでこれを待つのはやめましょう
I ask this question is now
この質問をするのは今です
Cutting-edge research that everyone is doing
誰もが取り組んでいる最先端の研究
it's not me
それは私ではありません
Instead, let's bring this up in exchange for this idea
代わりに、このアイデアと引き換えにこれを取り上げましょう
can there be some new ways
何か新しい方法はないでしょうか
Of course, this is to manage sunlight, air and water.
もちろん、太陽光、空気、水を管理するためです。
Right, we just needed three things and that's it
そうです、必要なのは 3 つだけで、それだけです
I'm not advertising for the tourist bureau
私は観光局の宣伝をしているわけではありません
But what I'm going to illustrate using this instruction
しかし、この命令を使って説明しようとしているのは、
It is how you manage sunlight, air and water
それは日光、空気、水を管理する方法です
ok let's look at the first thing
さて、最初に見てみましょう
Sunshine is just this
サンシャインはまさにこれ
Right, the first thing is the light
そう、まずは光です
Now if you look at the current solar panels
さて、現在のソーラーパネルを見てみると
will still shine
まだ輝くだろう
When it is replaced, there will be light reflection back, it is not used
交換すると光が反射してしまい使用されなくなります。
It doesn't work. You better suck all the light in.
それはうまくいきません。光をすべて吸い込んだほうがいいです。
right
右
And bacteria are useful
そしてバクテリアは役に立つ
this is the biggest
これが一番大きいです
There is no principle of heat to tell you that some light must be reflected back
一部の光が反射しなければならないという熱の原理はありません。
you just need
あなただけが必要です
common now
現在普遍
It doesn't matter if it's made of bacteria or glass
細菌でもガラスでも関係ない
Some of the light is reflected
光の一部が反射する
that's wasted
それは無駄だ
Organisms can be completely bacteria
生物は完全に細菌になることもある
It's the perfunctory of the black forehead
黒い額のおざなりだよ
it is also a perfunctory
それはおざなりでもある
that is, each one is
つまり、それぞれが
Each of these is a cell
それぞれが細胞です
And then a further fine-grained structure looks like this
そして、さらに細かい構造は次のようになります
it's going to be all black
真っ黒になるだろう
what is the reason
理由は何ですか
It only comes out in the middle of the night against time
時間との関係で夜中にしか出てこない
night
夜
words at night
夜の言葉
shine a little light on you
あなたに少しの光を当ててください
Others saw it and ate it
他の人もそれを見て食べました
So it is completely non-reflective
なので完全無反射です
Let's look at this physics principle first
まずこの物理原理を見てみましょう
Principles of Physics
物理原理
if i have two things
私に二つの物があるとしたら
one glass one air
一杯のグラス、一杯の空気
only one interface
インターフェイスは 1 つだけ
two rings
2つのリング
Then everyone has learned the light will go on
そうすれば誰もが光が灯ることを知った
then there will be a part
それから部分があるでしょう
regardless of reflection
反射とは関係なく
It depends on the difference between the two dielectric coefficients.
それは 2 つの誘電率の差によって決まります。
If it's glass and air, there's a big difference.
ガラスと空気では大きな違いがあります。
The difference is very big because the air is very cellular
空気は非常に細胞性が高いため、その違いは非常に大きくなります。
Boundary electrical coefficient is almost 1
境界電気係数はほぼ 1
About 2.5 for glass
ガラスの場合約2.5
That's not the dielectric coefficient this refractive index
それは誘電率ではなく、この屈折率です
But if you have a layer of coating in the middle
しかし、真ん中にコーティングの層がある場合は、
The dielectric coefficient of this coating is between these two
このコーティングの誘電率はこれら 2 つの間の値です
You will reflect less at this time
現時点ではあまり反省しないでしょう
it certainly looks like two chances
確かにチャンスは2回あるように見える
But every time it comes out less
でも毎回出てくる量が減っていきます
The best situation is infinite layers from here to here
最高の状況はここからここまで無限のレイヤーです
something from the index of refraction of a glass
ガラスの屈折率から何か
Until the air changes continuously
空気が変わり続けるまで
That black forehead is done and that's it
その黒い額は完成しました、それで終わりです
it does this structure
それはこの構造をします
You look like a protocone from the side
横から見るとプロトコーンみたいだね
Then periodically
それから定期的に
Then you can see that there are fewer and fewer things that can be blamed.
そうすれば、責められるべきことがどんどん減っていくことがわかります。
that is from
それはからです
Looking at it layer by layer
層ごとに見てみると
Refractive index decreases from now on
これから屈折率が下がっていく
In the end, all the light goes down without reflection
結局、すべての光は反射せずに消えます
In this case
この場合
I think
私が思うに
should be
あるべきです
is a do
することです
A good material for solar panels
ソーラーパネルに適した材料
The light that goes in doesn't come out
入った光が出てこない
this black thing
この黒いもの
of course
もちろん
people
人々
Noticed this early on and now figured out how to do this
早い段階でこれに気づき、これを行う方法を考え出しました
tie this
これを結びます
but not for solar cells
ただし太陽電池用ではない
Solar cells are not so expensive now
太陽電池は今ではそれほど高価ではありません
say in stealth plane
ステルス機で言う
stealth plane
ステルス飛行機
That electromagnetic wave owned by that stealth plane
あのステルス機が持つあの電磁波
from that
そこから
microwaves to this visible light
マイクロ波をこの可視光に照射
The entire spectrum is completely non-reflective
スペクトル全体が完全に無反射です
that's black
それは黒です
then you can't see
それなら見えないよ
In fact, this research
実はこれに関する研究では、
Central Plains Institute is doing well
セントラルプレーンズ研究所は順調です
these two
この二つ
Because of Chen Guixian
陳桂仙のせいで
Because it was originally locked because Lin Yuxiong was too big and there were too many forests
林玉雄が大きすぎて森が多すぎるため、もともとロックされていたため
is next door to me he is actually next door
彼は私の隣にいます、彼は実際に隣にいます
so i know what they do
だから私は彼らが何をしているのか知っています
They specialize in doing a lot of one-dimensional
彼らは一次元のオリジナルチェイスを多く行うことに特化しています
I just said that he wants to follow the original type
彼はオリジナルのタイプを踏襲したいと言っただけです
Raw chai materials, you can see that they make all kinds of materials
チャイの原料、いろんな材料を作っているのがわかります
This desalination plus fine arts, shower plus and so on these materials
この淡水化に美術、浸出などの材料を加えたものです。
how to do it i'm not talking too much
どうすればいいですか、あまり話していません。
I'm just talking about the application of the so-called plasma
私はいわゆるプラズマの応用について話しているだけです
or plasma discharge
またはプラズマ放電
Then release all kinds of temperament
それからあらゆる種類の気質を解放します
Temperament needed If you want to do desalination
脱塩をしたい場合は気質が必要です
You just put the thin bowl and this bowl down
薄いボウルとこのボウルを置くだけです
then excited in the plasma
その後プラズマ中で励起される
Break it down into molecules and start to grow
分子に分解して成長し始める
This is a device for microwave discharge of plasma
プラズマをマイクロ波放電させる装置です
They made it in 2007
彼らは2007年にそれを成し遂げました
I haven't asked them lately
最近は聞いていない
they should be
彼らはする必要があります
There is more progress and improvement
さらなる進歩と改善があります
will be to the whole world
全世界になるだろう
This is the original
これがオリジナルです
this
これ
This is their original one
これは彼らのオリジナルです
Silicon Wife
シリコンワイフ
Then after it grows this colorful coding
それが成長した後、このカラフルなコーディングが行われます
is black
黒です
Then this reflective green word
それからこの反射する緑の単語
about percent
約パーセント
one percent
1パーセント
maybe less than one percent
もしかしたら1パーセントにも満たないかもしれない
a few tenths of a percent
数十分のパーセント
It's a very black thing
すごく黒い、すごく黒い。
this is one
これは 1 つです
imitate this black forehead
この黒い額を真似してください
such a thing
そんなこと
Their materials do well is to say
彼らの材料はそう言うのに十分です
in each band
各バンドで
This reflex is close to the time collar
この反射はタイムカラーに近い
this is their material
これは彼らの資料です
made with fine
上質で作られた
This is outside the visible photon line
これは目に見えるフォトンラインの外側にあります
follow up infrared band
フォローアップ赤外線帯域
This is the mid-infrared band
これが中赤外線帯域です
just wave longer
もっと長く手を振ってください
still very low
まだ非常に低い
And then to the far infrared
そして遠赤外線へ
got a little higher
少し高くなりました
This bankruptcy has been very long
この破産は非常に長い間続いている
Until the microwave is relatively high
電子レンジが比較的高温になるまで
This material is such a
この素材はこんな感じです
Of course, microwaves are also available.
もちろん電子レンジもご利用いただけます。
It is also possible that its materials have to be further evolved
素材もさらに進化させなければならない可能性もある。
maybe they already have
もしかしたら彼らはすでに持っているかもしれない
Didn't find them today
今日は見つかりませんでした
That's the job of Academia Sinica
それが中央研究院の仕事です
I think I am obliged to introduce the work of Academia Sinica today
今日は中央研究院の研究を紹介する義務があると思います
so
それで
The second thing to talk about is
2番目に話すことは、
Heat management How to manage heat
熱管理 熱管理の方法
these guys
こいつら
Managing heat is a master
熱管理は達人です
Polar bears can survive temperatures as low as minus 50 degrees
ホッキョクグマはマイナス50度の気温でも生きられる
life without problems
問題のない生活
no problem at all
全く問題なし
but
しかし
yes it can
はい、できます
This is completely mentioned and does not spread out
これは完全に言及されていて広まりません
you give you a hint of this
あなたはこれのヒントを与えます
If you take an infrared
赤外線を撮ると
And the band is almost 10 micrometers
バンドはほぼ10マイクロメートルです
that infrared
その赤外線
there is an infrared
赤外線があります
Use that band to take pictures of the one in Beijing
そのバンドを使って北京のバンドの写真を撮ってください
They went to take pictures in the ice and snow
彼らは氷と雪の中で写真を撮りに行きました
With visible light, you can still see Beijing
可視光なら北京も見える
you use that infrared camera
あなたはその赤外線カメラを使っています
you can't see
あなたには見えません
except where its nose is
鼻があるところを除いて
you can see the nose
鼻が見えます
but the body can't see
でも体は見えない
is that it manages heat very well
それは熱をうまく管理しているということです
Its temperature is the same as the ice coat next to it
その温度は隣のアイスコートと同じです
it even reflectivity
それは反射率さえも
Infrared reflectivity is the same
赤外線反射率は同じ
it can do this
それはこれができます
blood on that band
そのバンドについた血
reflect with this
これで反省する
its this fur
この毛皮です
this is its fur
これはその毛皮です
It also has thick subcutaneous death of course
もちろん厚い皮下デスもあります
It died 10 cm under the skin
皮膚下10cmで死亡
then he is so thick
それから彼はとても太いです
subcutaneous wings
皮下翅膀
This is of course adiabatic
もちろん断熱です
then on top is hair
その上に髪の毛があります
He has fur with a unique design on it
彼は独特のデザインの毛皮を持っています
this is his hair
これは彼の髪です
electron microscope
電子顕微鏡
he is empty
彼は空っぽだ
If we cut up human hair and look at it
人間の髪の毛を切って見てみると
go see that is real
それが本物であるか見に行ってください
but
しかし
polar bear hair
シロクマの毛
Looks like there are a lot of holes in the middle
真ん中に穴がたくさんあるように見えます
The hair is transparent if you take it directly.
直接取ると髪の毛が透けて見えます。
quite transparent hair
かなり透明感のある髪
A lot of transparent things accumulate on the body
体に透明なものがたくさん溜まる
looks white
白く見える
this is no problem
これは問題ありません
Light range
光範囲
But it's this hollow design
しかし、それはこの空虚なデザインです
makes his infrared
彼の赤外線を作る
This is the electromagnetic wave I just talked about
これが先ほどお話しした電磁波です
top down
トップダウン
It's the same head now
今も同じ頭だよ
fever
熱
The temperature inside is 37 degrees
室内温度は37度
he has infrared
彼は赤外線を持っています
He makes a perfect greenhouse effect
彼は完璧な温室効果を生み出します
Infrared rays are emitted from the body
赤外線は体から出ています
completely blocked
完全にブロックされた
The basic truth is this
基本的な真実はこれです
it
それ
Except for the hairy hollow, is it air?
毛深い空洞以外は空気でしょうか？
so hot
とても暑い
Heat conduction has this heat conduction and this heat radiation
熱伝導にはこの熱伝導とこの熱放射があります
If it conducts heat, it relies on this hollow
熱を伝えるならこの空洞に頼る
And relying on the casting of these pass buttons
そして、これらのパスボタンのキャストに依存しています
This is the heat conduction itself
これは熱伝導そのものです
In addition, thermal radiation
また、熱放射も
Produced in
生産国
Its body temperature produces heat radiation that is about the same
体温はほぼ同じ熱放射を発生します
The broken long infrared rays of 10 micrometers
10マイクロメートルの壊れた長赤外線
It's going to block that infrared ray
赤外線を遮断してくれるんですね
this is its body
これがその本体です
its heat source
その熱源
The refractive index of infrared rays
赤外線の屈折率
gradually clear up
徐々に晴れていく
reduce
減少
to the last words
最後の言葉まで
Infrared rays are always reflected back
赤外線は必ず反射して戻ってきます
every time there is
あるたびに
Equal reflection effect
均等な反射効果
I won't come out until the end
最後まで出てこないよ
Its body temperature can be maintained
体温を維持できる
you can keep
あなたは保つことができます
This is light management
これが光の管理です
good
良い
Another kind of light management is sea urchin
もう一つの光管理はウニです
sea ​​urchin is such a guy
ウニはこんな奴だよ
The meat is delicious when you open it inside.
中を開けると肉が美味しいです。
this is expensive chicken
これは高価な鶏肉です
this
これ
very expensive japanese food
とても高価な日本食
this creature
この生き物
it grows many times
それは何倍にも成長します
it's very hard
とても難しい
It's hard to back off
後退するのは難しい
carbon brick cover
カーボンレンガカバー
I'm probably talking about the structure inside the four
おそらく4つの内部構造について話しているのでしょう
it contains living organisms
生物が含まれています
it's an animal on a gun
それは銃を持った動物です
have mouth
口がある
this is its mouth
これがその口です
anal groove
肛門槽上
on the anal groove
肛門の溝に
It's counterclockwise and counterclockwise
反時計回りと反時計回りです
mouth and teeth
口と歯
Then you see four is this
そうすると、4つがこれです
ice cube long block four
アイスキューブロングブロック4
In addition it can be moved
さらに移動も可能
it has this string
この文字列があります
can move
移動できる
I'm interested in this part
この部分に興味があります
if you touch it
あなたがそれに触れたら
it will move immediately
それはすぐに動きます
That time will move the direction
その時間が方向を変えるだろう
will be towards you
あなたに直面します
because you are the enemy
あなたは敵だから
it's facing you
それはあなたに向かって来ています
so you can't hold it
だからあなたはそれを保持することができません
can't move it
動かせない
It's an optical fiber except this
これ以外は光ファイバーです
it's a nice crystal
素敵な結晶ですね
Then the crystal pours light into it
するとクリスタルがそこに光を注ぎます
it is an optical fiber
それは光ファイバーです
The sea urchin turns into a shadow by this
これでウニが影になる
There is an incentive to subsidize it
補助金を出すインセンティブがある
For example, a crab comes to eat
たとえば、カニが食べに来ます。
Crabs are powerful and will eat sea urchins
カニは力が強いのでウニも食べます
turn it over
それを裏返し
i dig inside
私は中を掘ります
But when it comes, there will be shadows
でもそれが来るときは影が出るだろう
or the fish will have a shadow on it
そうしないと魚に影がついてしまいます
It adds this change of light
この光の変化を加えます
I think the management of this light is very powerful
この光の管理は非常に強力だと思います
The three-layer cover
三層構造のカバー
If you go outside Taroko to step on the marble
太魯閣の外に出て大理石を踏むと
Taroko, you only need one piece of this thing when you pick it up
タロコさん、これを拾うときに必要なのは 1 個だけです
Call Calsan such a hard and solid thing
こんなに硬くてしっかりしたものをカルサンと呼んでください
but sea urchin stone looks like this
でもウニ石はこんな感じ
so
それで
this is a short stone
これは短い石です
Then the barrel junction looks like this
するとバレルジャンクションはこんな感じになります
This is a juvenile sea urchin
こちらはウニの稚魚です
this is an adult
これは大人です
it is a hole with many holes
それは穴がたくさんある穴です
But the whole piece is a single body
しかし、全体は単一の体です
What is a single meridian body? That is, if you use X-rays on it
単一の経絡体とは何ですか? つまり、それに X 線を使用すると、
to rap
ラップする
you see six o'clock
6時が見えますね
not a ring
指輪ではありません
In other words, all scriptures and phases are consistent
言い換えれば、すべての経典と位相は一貫しています
a single body
単一の体
But obviously there's a lot of organic matter in there.
しかし、そこには明らかに有機物がたくさんあります。
clamped with it
それで締め付けられた
It forms a very unique single
非常にユニークなシングルになります
such a monotony
そんな単調な
That's because there's a lot of organic matter in it
有機物が多く含まれているからです
makes it hard to break
壊れにくくなる
You've eaten Bunker and you know it
バンカーを食べたことがあるならわかるでしょう
Bunker is better than this booth
このブースよりもバンカーの方が良い
It's hard for you to bomb it with inorganic matter
無機物で爆撃するのは難しい
It's hard, you can't hit it if you hit it vertically
硬いよ、垂直に打ったら当たらないよ
What is it, a lot of organic matter in the middle
なんだろう、真ん中に有機物がたくさんある
Electricity will dissipate its power
電気は電力を消費します
An inorganic, naturally occurring mineral
天然に存在する無機鉱物
Hit it vertically and it will break
垂直に叩くと壊れます
So it has a certain Indian
つまり、特定のインド人がいます
In addition it is a monolithic light
さらにモノリシックライトです
Yes delivery is very efficient
はい、配達は非常に効率的です
So it's an organic and inorganic load
つまり、それは有機的および無機的な負荷です
Inorganic part is carbon brick cover
無機部分はカーボンレンガカバー
The organic part is complicated
有機的な部分は複雑です
probably this glycoprotein
おそらくこの糖タンパク質
single body
単体
And then, a light guide
そして、ライトガイドがあります
It is also a transmitter of feeling power
感じる力の発信機でもあります
Because it is hard, it is very sensitive to feel the force
硬いので力を感じるのがとても敏感です
There's something out there that feels as soon as it touches it
触れた瞬間に感じる何かがある
The laboratory wants to imitate
研究室は真似したい
Is it possible to make this hole worry
この穴を心配させることは可能ですか？
This is something I made in my lab
これは私が研究室で作ったものです
carbon brick cover
カーボンレンガカバー
is in the form of a special carbon brick cover called Voltaire
Voltaire と呼ばれる特殊なカーボンレンガカバーの形をしています。
it is hexagonal body
六角形の本体です
Urea and glue
尿素と接着剤
In the small threshold, the collagen in Gelatin
小さな閾値では、ゼラチン中のコラーゲン
It reacts at a high temperature of more than 100 degrees
100度以上の高温で反応する
The economy made looks like a single catty
作られた経済は一斤のように見える
Then the X-ray evidence and Peng Huan's evidence know
X線証拠と彭環の証拠が分かる
It's the projectile, there's nothing wrong with it
それは発射体です、何も問題ありません
But this economic
しかし、この経済的
open it up and take a closer look
開いてよく見てください
first time i see this next big jump
次の大きなジャンプを初めて見た
because of many holes
穴がたくさんあるので
the kind you know
あなたが知っている種類
The kind that helps a whole piece
作品全体を助けるタイプ
The body is different
体が違うんだよ
it's obviously a pound
それは明らかにポンドです
because it has spirit and horns
魂と角があるから
Spirit and horns
精霊と角
but there are many holes in it
でも穴がたくさんある
Those are the collagen I added
これらは私が追加したコラーゲンです
After burning the collagen
コラーゲンを燃焼させた後
find many holes
たくさんの穴を見つける
Then I call it porous single catty
それから私はそれを多孔性シングルキャティと呼びます
This is like the result of a sea urchin
これはウニの結果のようです
You must have some
いくつか持っているはずです
Kidney knots are, gallbladder knots are
腎臓の結び目は、胆嚢の結び目です
there will be some points
いくつかのポイントがあるでしょう
just didn't grow up
ただ成長しなかっただけ
When you grow up, you'll be in so much pain
大人になったら、とても苦しいことになるだろう
I need to see a doctor
医者に診てもらう必要がある
Those deadlines are guts too
締め切りも根性だ
But this apple meal lid
でもこのアップルミールの蓋は
They can make this kind of
彼らはこのようなものを作ることができます
This kind of good optical properties
このような良好な光学特性
I'm not going to talk about his optical nutrition
彼の光学栄養学については話すつもりはありません
Simply because he is guts
ただ彼は根性があるから
A small relationship but a lot of holes in it
小さな関係だけど穴はたくさんある
if the hole goes in something else
穴が他のものに入ってしまったら
you can sense him
あなたは彼を感じることができます
do other things
他のことをする
to say is to say
言うことは言うことです
Organisms manage this light very efficiently
生物はこの光を非常に効率的に管理します
This is proof that he has guts
これは根性がある証拠だ
This uses the point of the electronic teacher
これは電子教師のポイントを使用します
Next I will talk about gas management
次にガス管理についてお話します。
what we just said
私たちが今言ったこと
If I want to make a fuel cell like that
そんな燃料電池を作りたいと思ったら
Or when it is solar battery of the decomposition of water
あるいは水の分解の太陽電池の場合
I want to manage this gas
このガスをなんとかしたい
ah what to do
ああ、どうしよう
Let's take a look at the structure of a bird's lungs
鳥の肺の構造を見てみましょう
it's a bird's lungs
それは鳥の肺です
Birds have the most powerful lungs of all living things
鳥はすべての生き物の中で最も強力な肺を持っています
the most powerful
最も強力な
When this eagle is fighting
このワシが戦っているとき
there is a lot of air
空気がたくさんある
And they fly high
そして彼らは高く飛びます
the air is thinner
空気が薄い
And some birds can fly as high as the Simara Mountains
そしていくつかの鳥はシマラ山脈と同じ高さまで飛ぶことができます
The density of air is only one-third of that of the earth's surface.
空気の密度は表面のわずか 3 分の 1 です
So its lung blood has a powerful function
そのため、肺の血液は強力な機能を持っています
The lungs are of course because of the exchange of air and blood
肺は当然、空気と血液の交換を行っています。
it is a two-fluid
それは二流体です
In terms of painters, it is a two-way fluid
ペインターの観点から言えば、それは双方向の流体です。
it has air bags
エアバッグが付いています
Then there are many very thin
それから非常に薄いものがたくさんあります
Hierarchical structure of this pipeline
このパイプラインの階層構造
air blood
空気の血
Then what they cross is theirs
そうすれば、彼らが交差するものは彼らのものです
We do exchange the molecule O2
O2分子を交換します
If you zoom in to see the details
拡大して詳細を確認すると
you see it is
そうですよね
It is the result of the concatenation formula I just mentioned.
先ほど述べた連結式の結果です。
It has the largest sac is the air sac
最大の嚢は気嚢です
Then there are these spaces in the middle
それから真ん中にこれらのスペースがあります
there is even less space
スペースはさらに少ない
space then the hole
スペース、それから穴
They conduct this flow of gas and liquid
この気体と液体の流れを伝導します。
There are some things that I can't figure out now. I'm not studying
今はわからないことがあるのですが、勉強していません。
Life I don't know which one is slippery and which one
人生どっちが滑るか分からない
liquid
液体
so
それで
The resolution diagram is like this
解像度図はこんな感じ
It is joined into the result of a large tube
それは大きな管状の結果に結合されます
To a small tube, ah, a smaller tube
小さな管に、ああ、もっと小さな管に
Then do this air flow
次に、この空気の流れを実行します
this is a blood vessel
これは血管です
have
もつ
very effective this exchange
この交換は非常に効果的です
From a rougher university
荒れた大学から
to this menace pavilion
この脅威のパビリオンへ
do this
これを行う
something like this
このようなもの
In terms of materials
素材的には
people just want to do
人々はただやりたいだけです
This is a porous material
これは多孔質の素材です
We've had trouble using this so far
これまでのところこれを使用するのに問題がありました
What makes protein such a material
タンパク質はそのような物質を作るものです
Apparently creatures can do
どうやら生き物はできるようだ
but we can always make inorganic
しかし、いつでも無機物を作ることができます
Inorganic material
無機物材料
Our laboratory makes materials with many holes
私たちの研究室では穴の多い材料を作っています
Its method is to take organic matter and inorganic matter
その方法は有機物と無機物を摂取することです
to self-install
自己インストールする
This is completely self-installed
これは完全に自己インストールです
one foot and it will form like this
片足だとこんな感じになります
This part is organic matter
この部分は有機物です
Then the next wall is
そうすると次の壁は
Dioxide is inorganic and hard
二酸化物は無機質で硬い
Finally you put the organic matter inside
最後に有機物を中に入れます
Burn off the collar or extract
首輪や抽出物を焼き切る
you make the hole
あなたが穴をあけます
the size of the hole
穴のサイズ
you can control
あなたはコントロールできます
Using the molecular size of this organic
この有機物の分子サイズを利用して
you control
あなたがコントロールします
Available from two Nami
ナミ2名から利用可能
to maybe dozens of nami
おそらく数十人のナミまで
Such a medium porous material
このような中多孔質材料
it's a water dragon coming out from corner to corner
隅から隅まで出てくるのはウォータードラゴンです
So it has all sorts of hierarchical results
したがって、あらゆる種類の階層的な結果が含まれます
you can control
あなたはコントロールできます
I can't speak here today
今日はここで話すことができません
I just show you one
一つだけお見せします
What does the electron micrograph look like
電子顕微鏡写真はどのように見えますか
its hole
その穴
This is from an interface to see it
これはインターフェースから見るためのものです
This is to start a
これは、
It has a variety of one tube is bent
一本の管が曲がって色々あります
this is a straight tube
これは直管です
This is the oxygen system
これが酸素システムです
this is a hole
これは穴です
OK, what about the porous material?
さて、多孔質素材についてはどうでしょうか？
Can progress to class
クラスに進むことができる
This is the one that the lab wants to imitate
研究室が真似したいのはこれだ
Hierarchical result approach
階層的結果アプローチ
This paper is not my paper
この論文は私の論文ではありません
this is
これは
it does is a hierarchical
それは階層的です
A large amount of gas can be quickly dispersed inside
大量のガスを素早く内部に分散させることができます。
into the tiny hole
小さな穴に
This gas is TNT
このガスはTNTです
prevent explosives
爆発物を防ぐ
when passing the airport now
今空港を通過するとき
they are most afraid of you
彼らはあなたを最も恐れています
yes there is this
はい、これがあります
this dynamite
このダイナマイト
TNT is an organic molecule
TNTは有機分子です
Three-way calculation plus this
三交計加本
This molecule is difficult for you to use
この分子はあなたにとって使いにくいです
this
これ
abandoned to detect it
それを探知するために放棄された
The best way is to develop an artificial pen
最善の方法は人工ペンを開発することです
artificial brush
人工筆子
That artificial pen is very sensitive
その人工ペンは非常に敏感です
That is to say, your gas can
つまり、ガス缶は
Scattered into a small hole, that small hole
小さな穴に散りばめられた、その小さな穴
run a detection version
検出バージョンを実行する
Well, I'm not talking about the detection version here, I'm talking about it's a god-like structure
まあ、私はここで検出バージョンについて話しているのではなく、それが神のような構造であるということについて話しています
From Big Hole, Medium Hole to Small Hole
大穴、中穴、小穴まで
This small hole is the size of a TNT molecule
この小さな穴はTNT分子ほどの大きさです
It used it as a template when it was originally made
作成時にテンプレートとして使用しました
This is the concept of template synthesis
これがテンプレート合成の概念です
I use it as a template when compositing, this is the red one
合成するときにテンプレートとして使用します。これは赤いものです
Other things that are silica
その他のシリカのもの
this template
このテンプレート
So when TNT comes
だからTNTが来たら
It just snaps in and can suck a lot
はめ込むだけでたくさん吸い込むことができます
No matter how big or small other molecules are,
他の分子がどんなに大きくても小さくても、
So it's very sensitive to selectivity
したがって、選択性に対して非常に敏感です
Then because it is a god-like structure
それなら神のような構造だから
From the big hole to the small hole in a short time
大きな穴から小さな穴まで短時間で
The past seems to be a life
過去は人生のようだ
The purpose is the same as the lungs or many small holes in the nose
目的は肺や鼻にあるたくさんの小さな穴と同じです
it can be smelled at once
すぐに匂いを嗅ぐことができる
This is gas management
これがガス管理です
used in this
この中で使われている
What I just said about batteries on carbon
カーボンバッテリーについて先ほど述べたこと
One of the things I just talked about is
今お話ししたことの 1 つは、
The material is carbon
素材はカーボンです
Then your porous carbon can also be made like this
そうすれば、多孔質カーボンもこのように作ることができます
Like the one just now, it's a carbon dioxide system
先ほどと同じく二酸化炭素系です
this is carbon
これはカーボンです
You can see that there are relatively large holes
比較的大きな穴が開いているのがわかります。
Then the big hole will be in the wall
そうすれば壁​​に大きな穴が開くだろう
there are many small holes
小さな穴がたくさんあります
Also, have you seen the battery?
あと、バッテリーを見ましたか？
inside the black and white part
その白と黒の部分で
there are even smaller holes
さらに小さな穴もあります
it is made of three
それは3つでできています
Let it load this Platinum Sharder on it
このプラチナシャーダーをロードさせてください
its this gas management is good
このガス管理は良好です
because big hole to small hole
大きな穴から小さな穴まで
In addition
加えて
All these carbons are linked together
これらすべての炭素は互いに結合しています
So its conductive path is connected
したがって、その導電パスは接続されています
no power outage
停電はありません
It can be done like this to adjust the battery
バッテリーを調整するには次のように行うことができます
Then its current versus voltage is the best
その場合、電流対電圧が最適になります
In comparison, activated carbon or platinum ridges can be used
それに比べて、活性炭や白金リッジも使用できます。
it performs much better
それははるかに優れたパフォーマンスを発揮します
This is a hierarchical bionic concept.
これは階層的なバイオニック概念です。
Of course it can be used as a reactor
もちろんリアクターとしても使えます
Our laboratory is in this Dadongqiao Cave
私たちの研究室はこの大洞橋洞窟にあります
full of various catalysts
様々な触媒が詰まった
then do the chemical reaction
それから化学反応をします
so soon
こんなに早く
react in a short time
短時間で反応する
I won't talk about it
それについては話さない
Okay, let's talk about water
はい、水について話しましょう
how water is managed
水はどのように管理されているのか
In a fuel cell just like that
燃料電池でも同じように
for example
例えば
hydrogenation of oxygen to electricity
酸素を水素化して電気を作る
Then it's water
それなら水だよ
Oxygen and hydrogen are poured in all the time
酸素と水素を常時注入
In fact, the water keeps coming out.
実際、水はどんどん出てきます。
How do you manage this water?
この水をどうやって管理しているのでしょうか？
is also an important thing
も重要なことです
if you don't manage
管理しないと
it blocks everything
それはすべてをブロックします
It will be more stressful to come in again
また来るとさらにストレスがたまる
you spend more
あなたはもっとお金を使います
your efficiency will decrease
効率が低下します
or at the end
または最後に
can't stay at all
全然居られない
stay in many places
多くの場所に滞在する
those with tiny holes
小さな穴があるもの
To manage the flow of this water
この水の流れをコントロールするために
this is a problem
これは問題だ
Well, we've just talked about this compounding effect
さて、この複合効果についてお話しました。
The compounding effect is one
複合効果は1つです
One way to manage water well
水を上手に管理する一つの方法
right
右
let's see
どれどれ
how from there
そこからどうやって
release to be bright
明るくなるように解放する
Let's look at the lotus leaf again
もう一度蓮の葉を見てみましょう
lotus leaf words
蓮の葉の言葉
it's a drop
それはドロップです
can be on this lotus leaf
この蓮の葉の上になれる
this slide
このスライド
The reason is the so-called contact angle
その理由はいわゆる接触角です
Very big
非常大
it's not collapsed
潰れてないよ
but rolled up
でも丸まった
rolled up state
丸めた状態
why is it like this
なぜこんなことになっているのか
Because it is related to this structure
この構造に関係しているので、
its a lot raised fog
かなり霧が上がってます
let's see
どれどれ
This so-called supertransportation
このいわゆる超交通機関は、
A strong wall of clear water
清水的一強壁
like glass
ガラスのように
Glass is a strong wall of clear water
ガラスは澄んだ水の強い壁です
just water will
水だけで済みます
Spread it flat and become a thin layer of water film
平らに広げて薄い水の膜になる
If you pour water, say spicy
水を注ぐと辛いと言ってください
if you put a spicy surface
スパイシーな表面を置くと
it will become a semicircle
半円になります
or something more than a semicircle
または半円以上のもの
But there is still an angle
でもまだ角度はある
That angle won't be 180 degrees
その角度は180度にはなりません
it will be there and stick there
それはそこにあり、そこに固執するでしょう
If a glass is heavily oiled
ガラスに油が大量に付着している場合
just can't get oil
ただ油が手に入らない
see a lot of water sticking to it
たくさんの水が付着しているのが見えます
on the leaf of the plant
植物の葉の上に
Of course it feels oily
もちろん油っぽい感じもしますが
it's already a bit of a loser
それはすでにちょっと負け組です
But it's not enough to say let that
しかし、それだけでは十分ではありません
that thing
その事
That droplet is easily in the liberalization
そのしずくは簡単に自由化に入る
it further this structure
さらにこの構造
There are all kinds of talk here
ここではあらゆる種類の話が行われます
This is the so-called Cassi state
これがいわゆるカッシ状態です
That is to say, it is easier for us to understand
つまり、私たちにとっても理解しやすいのです
That is to let this water
それは、これに水を与えることです
Go to bed of nails for that yogi guru in india
インドのヨガの第一人者のために釘のベッドに行きましょう
isn't a yoga guru a lot of bed of nails
ヨガの達人ではないのですか？
that has a lot of nails on it
それには釘がたくさん付いています
Then the master lay down
それからマスターは横になりました
You hang it vertically, what are you doing?
縦に吊るしてますが、何をしているのですか？
right
右
Then we just let the water
それから水をやるだけです
Drops of water to make this bed
このベッドを作るための一滴の水
when he was in bed
彼がベッドにいたとき
he doesn't want to go down
彼は下がりたくない
Because the surface tension
表面張力があるので、
too much energy not to slip out
エネルギーが多すぎて抜け出せない
he won't go down
彼は降りません
If he doesn't go down, he will roll up.
彼が下がらなければ、転がってしまうだろう。
This is what causes the so-called superspeed water benefit
これが、いわゆる超高速水の利点を引き起こす原因です。
if the plant is on that lotus leaf
もしその植物がその蓮の葉の上にあれば
Basically this is enough
基本的にはこれで十分です
But if the lotus leaf goes further
でも蓮の葉がさらに進めば
is the combination of these two Nami
この二人のナミの組み合わせです
with micron
ミクロンで
This is its micron scale
これがミクロンスケールです
This is the scale of difficulty
これが難易度の目安です
it combines two
それは2つを組み合わせます
This water transfer is more efficient
この水の移動はより効率的です
I won't talk about the details there
そこでは詳細については話しません
don't talk too much over there
そこではあまり話さないでください
This is to introduce
これを紹介するのは、
The other one is that you say it slides
もう一つは、スライドするということです
if there is something on it
そこに何かがある場合
is a plain spicy surface
プレーンなスパイシーな表面です
it or glass surface
それまたはガラス表面
It will stick and stay still
くっついて動くよ
it doesn't move at last
ついに動かない
But if it's a speeding water like this
でも、こんな激流なら
it not only understands
それは理解するだけではありません
And it will take the tension away
そしてそれは緊張を和らげます
So the filthy bastard dripped to the roll
それで汚い野郎がロールに滴り落ちた
This oneness shows that it is clean
この一体性は清潔であることを示しています
very clean without dust
ほこりもなくとてもきれい
So we say that you will not be stained by the fog
だから霧に染まらないって言うよ
So there's a lot of application here
ここにはたくさんのアプリケーションがあります
For example, the lenses of your glasses
たとえば、メガネのレンズ
with superfast water on it
超高速水がかかっている
so you don't get foggy
曇らないように
your camera
あなたのカメラ
Best Camera Lenses Top Now
現在トップのベストカメラレンズ
treated with ultra-fast water
超高速水で処理
It won't get foggy if it gets water droplets on it
水滴がついても曇らない
The next thing I want to introduce is the work of Academia Sinica
次に紹介したいのは中央研究院の取り組みです。
It belongs to Dr. Chen Peilin from the Ink Center
インクセンターのチェン・ペイリン博士のものです。
he's here ask him a question
彼はここにいます、彼に質問してください
He just figured out how to do it in this one
彼はちょうどこれでそれを行う方法を見つけました
The solid surface makes that like a lycium
デイジーをイメージしたしっかりとした表面感
raised structures on leaves
葉の上の隆起した構造
The method is to use this sphere implicit in a script
この球体をスクリプト内で暗黙的に使用する方法です。
can be made into a very uniform ball
非常に均一なボールを作ることができます
then use this
それからこれを使ってください
this
これ
It should be Shi Wen's.
それはシー・ウェンのもののはずだ。
This plasma allows the plasma to eliminate sugar
この血漿により、血漿は糖を除去することができます
remove sugar
砂糖を取り除く
Little Five Seconds looks like this
リトルファイブセカンズはこんな感じ
smaller than look
見た目より小さい
It disappears like this in fifty seconds
50秒後にはこのまま消えてしまう
Then you look like a spit
そうするとあなたは唾吐きのように見えます
If you continue to eliminate, you will exhale more
排出し続けると吐き出す量が増える
so
それで
Then
それから
departmental complex
部門複合体
It has ribs that modify the surface
表面を修正するリブが付いています
Then there is the flow
それから流れがあります
I won't go into that detail
その詳細には立ち入りません
the point is
ポイントは
After these plasma demagnetization
これらのプラズマ消磁後
cause a lot of aspirates
大量の誤嚥を引き起こす
Finally, from the contact angle
最後に接触角から
It's the original shape of 115 degrees.
115度のオリジナル形状です。
to the last one hundred and fifty one
最後の百五十一まで
Actually it can do 170 degrees maybe
実際には170度もできるかもしれない
But it's hard to do 190 degrees
でも190度にするのは難しい
Rolled away because of a slight shock
軽い衝撃で転がってしまった
Three rolls of that thing
それを3ロール
That's the butt bed effect
それがバットベッド効果です
butt bed effect
バットベッド効果
under different cutting conditions
さまざまな切削条件で
if its exhalation condition is different
呼気の状態が違う場合
The contact angle ended up being close to 180 degrees
接触角は180度近くになりました
this is a
これは
bound
バウンド
concept to do
やるべきコンセプト
When he was almost unified
彼がほぼ統一されたとき
Chen Peining this job
チェン・ペイニンのこの仕事
In addition, the future of Chinese scientists
さらに、中国の科学者の将来
He later made great achievements in this field
彼は後にこの分野で大きな功績を残した
They use various tests
彼らはさまざまなテストを使用します
Chemistry collaborators make closer to that
化学の共同研究者がそれに近づく
the lotus
蓮
The structure of the synthetic surface
合成表面の構造
he uses this
彼はこれを使います
He uses an electrical method
彼は電気的な方法を使っています
So make a polymer square
それでポリマーを正方形にします
or make a ball to many divisions
または多くの部門にボールを作る
he can do well
彼はうまくやれる
this
これ
this drop of water is on top
この水滴は上にあります
arrangement of carbon tubes
カーボンチューブの配置
This is the one from Beijing Academy of Sciences
これは北京科学院のものです
main road book
主道本
carbon nanotubes
カーボンナノチューブ
there is another one that does
するものはもう一つあります
It's also the top bed
こちらも最上段のベッドです
This is more like the top bed of an Indian master
これはインドのマスターの一番上のベッドに似ています
let the bottom be on top
下が上になるようにします
Then work is what I can control
そうなると、仕事は私がコントロールできるものです
i can control him
私は彼をコントロールできる
I see the surface
表面が見えています
turn into crisp water
さわやかな水に変わります
super crisp water
超酥水
Turn into ultra-clear water at once
一気に超透明水に変身
Just spread some ingredients on top
上に材料を塗るだけ
this guy
この男
to this thing outside
外のこの物に
let it fall
落とす
This section is backwater
この区間は背水の陣です
then the whole will be out of water
そうすると全体が水からなくなってしまいます
In addition to the puzzling structure just mentioned
先ほど述べた不可解​​な構造に加えて、
for which the structure will exceed
構造がそれを超える
Then when it stops, it's clear water
そしてそれが止まると、それは透明な水です
So this water will be collected and turned into a ball once it is dipped in water.
したがって、この水は水に浸されると集められ、ボールになります。
Very precise control over water
水を非常に正確に制御
For example, this is the contact angle
たとえば、これは接触角です
Contact angle
接触角
Then this Cosmite can do the control of this track
その後、この Cosmite がこのトラックのコントロールを行うことができます
After this electrical control
この電気制御の後
Or PH control can be done
またはPHコントロールも可能
This is an example of an electrical control
これは電気制御の一例です
A liquid approaches 180 degrees from the contact angle
液体は接触角から180度に近づく
Change the voltage with control
コントロールで電圧を変える
fall
秋
spread out
広がる
many degrees
何度も
That
それか
of course japanese
もちろん日本人です
sell it quickly
早く売りなさい
Japan combined light blowing agent
日本配合光発泡剤
What is produced is ultra-clear water and super-water
生み出されるのは超清水・超水
On the surface this is super salary
表面的にはこれは超給与です
can make this surface very smooth
この表面を非常に滑らかにすることができます
So if it is reflected in the rearview mirror of the car, it will not fog up
車のバックミラーに映っても曇りません
good
良い
just that particle
その粒子だけ
haven't really used it yet
まだ実際には使っていません
I originally spoke about this fuel cell
私は最初にこの燃料電池について話しました
its management
その管理
But it shouldn't be possible to imagine
でもそれは想像できないはず
what can be done
何ができるか
the flowing water
流れる水
Make super pay for the water when it pours
水が注がれたら、超高額の料金を支払います
Then its gas flow and liquid flow will not block each other
そうすれば、気体の流れと液体の流れが互いに妨げられなくなります。
Because it, the liquid is suspended on some hollows
一部の窪みに液体が浮遊しているため、
gas flow
ガスの流れ
nose does not interfere heavily
鼻が大きく干渉しない
No blocking, no flotting
ブロッキングや浮き上がりがありません
Batteries made in a pro-family reaction
家族擁護の反応で作られたバッテリー
produce water, this water can
水を生成します、この水はできます
very easy
非常に簡単
because it slides easily
滑りやすいので
it can flow
それは流れることができる
So in doing the management
それでマネジメントをする上で
water management
水的management
Apparently that should also help
どうやらそれも役立つはずです
Finally I'll talk about catalysts
最後に触媒についてお話します
you want to do this
あなたはこれをしたいのですか
What is the most basic chemical reaction
最も基本的な化学反応は何ですか
there is a chemical reaction
化学反応があります
new example
新しい例
becomes H2
H2になる
right? get electrons get electrons from electrodes
そうでしょう? 電子を取得します 電極から電子を取得します
Or H2 conversely means that H2 becomes a new example
または、H2 は逆に、H2 が新しい例になることを意味します
Then the new example has to be traditionally ground to the other end
次に、新しい例を伝統的に反対側の端まで研磨する必要があります
Then H2 becomes a new example is the lost electron
次に、H2 は失われた電子の新しい例になります。
To do this thing, that depends on a shattered body
このことをするには、粉々になった体が必要だ
I was talking about platinum
プラチナの話してた
I pay more attention to the oxygen head on the other end.
私は反対側の酸素ヘッドに注目します。
Oxygen headers are also
酸素ヘッダーも
Oxygen O2
酸素O2
The first thing it needs to accept electrons to become O2-
O2になるためにはまず電子を受け取る必要があります-
that's the first step
それが最初のステップです
Then step by step it becomes
その後、段階的に次のようになります
Platinum is too expensive
プラチナは高すぎる
What we just said, if it is really made of platinum
今言ったこと、それが本当にプラチナでできているなら
we can't go on
続けられない
This is what the sun can't do
これは太陽にはできないことだ
Because the reserves of platinum on the earth are simply not enough
地球上のプラチナの埋蔵量はまったく足りないからです
effective number
有効数
Organisms have long been able to manage this oxygen
生物は古くからこの酸素を管理することができました
BOSS movement
BOSS的運動
All of us breathe in oxygen
私たちは皆、酸素を吸い込んでいます
we do things with it
私たちはそれを使って何かをします
I'm here to talk about a relatively simple
ここでは比較的単純なことについて話したいと思います
This is what our lab is doing
これが私たちの研究室がやっていることです
It's really easier to do
本当に簡単にできるようになりました
It is not just H2 plus O2 to change water directly
水を変えるのはH2とO2だけではありません
I just do a simple response is this
簡単な返答をするだけです
O2 receives an electron to become superoxide
O2は電子を受け取ってスーパーオキシドになります
This superoxide is receiving electrons to turn into hydrogen peroxide in two instructions
このスーパーオキシドは電子を受け取り、2 つの命令で過酸化水素に変化します。
There is a efficacious number that looks like this
こんな感じの有効な数字があります
It's called SOD
SODといいます
super oxo coal
スーパーオキソコール
it is a coal
それは石炭です
Of course, other effects can be used later to turn this into water and oxygen.
もちろん、後で他のエフェクトを使用して、これを水と酸素に変えることもできます。
Then I can raise it and then dig it up.
それからそれを育てて、それを掘ることができます。
Its last can turn O2 into H2
最後はO2をH2に変えることができます
This is a reaction to the grading we just talked about
これは先ほど話したグレーディングに対する反応です
It's Yang Ji's reaction
ヤンジの反応です
I don’t need the common people to tell me to help me make an effect
一般人に「効果を出すのを手伝って」なんて言われる必要はない
But this effect, if you really take it seriously
でもこの効果、真剣に考えると
It feels like you have to raise a lot of big factories
大きな工場をたくさん建てないといけないような気がする
Then go to performance
その後はパフォーマンスへ
That is also an important thing
それも高価です
Is there a way we can make a compound
化合物を作る方法はありますか
That compound mimics this potency
その化合物はこの効能を模倣します
This is bionic
これはバイオニックです
If you make this compound to imitate this effect
この効果を模倣してこの化合物を作ると
Then let's see the effect
それでは効果を見てみましょう
What's the result in the middle
真ん中の結果は何ですか
It doesn't matter what this page does to protein and what to us
このページがタンパク質にどう影響するか、私たちにどう影響するかは関係ありません。
Let's look at the middle one
真ん中のものを見てみましょう
on the next page
次のページで
it's here
ここにあります
This is the only chemical structure that appears in my entire speech
これは私のスピーチ全体に登場する唯一の化学構造です
I'm sorry if you don't study chemistry imitation
化学もどきの勉強してない人はごめんなさい
I only focus on a copper
私は銅だけに焦点を当てています
There's copper with a bunch of protein molecules in the middle
銅が中心にたくさんのタンパク質分子を持っています
there today
今日はそこに
Focus on this
これに焦点を当ててください
This copper is the center of its active point
この銅はその活性点の中心です
I just talked about this super sheep molecule
先ほどこのスーパーシープ分子について話しました
Souff Osley reacted to him and became O2
スフ・オスリーは彼に反応し、O2になった
B has O2 coming out
BはO2が出ています
copper becomes copper
銅は銅になる
Then it becomes H2O2 with another long-term oxygen molecule.
その後、別の長時間の酸素分子とともに H2O2 になります。
The reaction I'm talking about now is this
今話している反応はこれです
Haven't used that electrical response yet
まだその電気的反応を使っていない
The electrical reaction requires the final change to water
電気反応には最終的に水への変化が必要です
let's start with this
これから始めましょう
Half of it is made by this Mars point
その半分はこの火星点によって作られています
But carefulness on the side is absolutely necessary
ただし、側面の注意は絶対に必要です
And this bridge to achieve such a central point
そしてこの橋はそのような中心点に到達するためのものです
The large pile of amine bricks next to it finally surrounded a very complicated result
その隣のアミンレンガの大きな山は、最終的に非常に複雑な結果を囲みました
then we want to say
それから私たちが言いたいのは
I first synthesize a molecule
まず分子を合成します
like this part
この部分のように
and placed inside a porous material
多孔質材料の内部に配置されます
like the outside part
外側の部分のように
I typed it like this
このように入力しました
Here is my bionic method
これが私のバイオニックメソッドです
we won't talk about the details
詳細については話しません
Chemosynthesis looks like a bit of a nuisance
化学合成はちょっと面倒そう
But it's not difficult
でも難しくないよ
it's my hole
それは私の穴です
that hole
那個洞
Didn't I just say that I make hole materials
今穴素材作るって言ったじゃないですか
delivery is possible
配達は可能です
Gas fluid enters quickly
ガス流体の侵入が早い
Then these molecules loaded are my
そうすると、読み込まれたこれらの分子は私のものです
mimic the molecule that eliminates
除去する分子を模倣する
it's going to be my catalyst
それは私の触媒になるでしょう
its synthesis gas has pentagon
その合成ガスは五角形をしています
I'm afraid I won't go into the details of its catalytic reaction here.
申し訳ありませんが、ここではその触媒反応の詳細には触れません。
This is what you will talk about if you are in the chemistry semester
これは、化学の学期にいる場合に話すことです
it is a circular reaction
それは循環反応です
the point is to say
ポイントは言うことです
This will be disconnected when the reaction is in the middle
反応途中で切断されます
This chemical room needs to be disconnected
この化学室は切断する必要があります
If this molecule is in aqueous solution, it will not be able to do work.
この分子が水溶液中にあると仕事をすることができません。
this loop won't run
このループは実行されません
because it has to be picked up again
もう一度拾わなければならないので
It won't work if you take it back
持ち帰ったらダメだよ
Just break up, break up, run away
別れて、別れて、逃げて
But I use this hole to lift it
でもこの穴を使って持ち上げるの
I just imitate it. The simple pendulum is the skeleton.
真似してるだけです、単純な振り子がスケルトンです。
like this
このような
i produce
私がプロデュースします
Use this molecule to sense this Super Oxide
この分子を使用してこのスーパーオキシドを感知します
Super Oxide is a
スーパーオキサイドは、
produced by an enzyme reaction
酵素反応によって生成される
I'm going to generate this superoxide molecule
このスーパーオキシド分子を生成します
to generate light
光を生成する
Then detect with this
次に、これで検出します
The way we detect its activity is by saying
その活動を検出する方法は次のとおりです。
How much catalytic converter is needed
触媒コンバーターはどのくらい必要ですか
can cut it in half
半分に切ることができます
This is called IC50
これをIC50といいます
IC50 Let's do 0 hours and 20
IC50 0時間20やってみよう
IC50 means that the higher the worse
IC50は高ければ高いほど悪いということを意味します
because you need a lot of catalyst
触媒がたくさん必要なので
to achieve the same effect
同じ効果を達成するために
the higher the worse
高ければ高いほど悪い
This is our catalyst itself
これは私たちの触媒そのものです
did not do other things
他のことはしませんでした
didn't let go and didn't do anything
手放さず何もしなかった
it's inactive
非アクティブです
And the activity is not good
そして活動も良くない
50%
５０％
After a design of the material which moves in various ways
様々に動く素材をデザインした上で
side mimic protein
サイドミミックプロテイン
surrounding structure
周囲の構造物
try to imitate it
それを真似してみてください
because we know protein
プロテインを知っているから
the result of that pin count
そのピン数の結果
I can get down to 1.9 at my best
ベストの場合は 1.9 まで下げることができます
Of course, this is not as good as the real effect.
もちろん、これは実際の効果ほど良いものではありません。
This real effect has an IC50 of 0.9
この実際の効果の IC50 は 0.9 です。
already very very good
すでにとてもとても良い
Then I want to tell you one thing is to say
そこで一つ言いたいのは、
don't you use platinum
プラチナは使わないの？
you do this
これをして
It's the reduction reaction
それは還元反応です
originally was
元々は
what all animals do
すべての動物がやること
Why are you going for platinum?
なぜプラチナを狙うのですか？
should go this way
こちらに行くべきです
but now
でも今
Almost no one goes this way yet
まだこの道を行く人はほとんどいない
But I think it will be needed in the future
でも将来的には必要になると思う
a path that needs to be taken
取るべき道
I won't talk about the details
詳細については話しません
This is a lot of material
これはたくさんの材料です
Various Designs for Being Human
人間であるためのさまざまなデザイン
i'm not going to be here today
今日はここにいないつもりです
good
良い
The final overall effect is this
最終的な全体的な効果はこれです
he reacted
彼は反応した
use one
用一個
simulated artificial effect
シミュレートされた人工効果
to achieve this
これを達成するために
add in small portions
少しずつ加える
Kong Dong's material
孔東的材料
Of course next we should do this
もちろん次はこれをやるべきです
Convert this again to one-half of the feed water
これを供給水の 1/2 に戻します。
The other level of response is the new
他のレベルの応答は新しいものです
it all adds up to
すべて合計すると
I want to finally make this Fuel Electronics Singayang
これを最終的には燃料エレクトロニクス・シンガヤンにしたいと思っています
Generate this electricity and water
この電気と水を生成します
Of course it's still early
もちろんまだ早いですよ
But this is a bionic idea
しかし、これはバイオニックなアイデアです
rather than an idea with an industrial catalytic period
産業革命期のアイデアではなく
Ok, finally I should make a short structure
さて、最後に短い構造を作成する必要があります
what i'm talking about today is
今日私が話していることは
Using Power in an Energy Problem
エネルギー問題における電力の利用
our generation
私たちの世代
and the problem that the next generation may face
そして次世代が直面するかもしれないこの問題
We will eventually convert to the sun's
私たちは最終的には太陽に変換します
We're going to design a chemical solar electron
私たちは太陽化学電子を設計するつもりです
convert solar energy into chemical
太陽エネルギーを化学物質に変換する
or fuel electronics
または燃料エレクトロニクス
convert to sunny
晴れに変える
which is then converted into electricity
それが電気に変換されます
The problem faced is to manage the light
直面する問題は光の管理です
Facing problems to manage water
水管理の問題に直面している
Facing Problems To Manage Gas
ガス管理で直面する問題
also manages catalytic
触媒も管理します
every step i think
私が考えるすべてのステップ
can be done with bionic methods
バイオニック手法で行うことができる
all can
すべてできる
If that day comes, we should do it very cheaply
その日が来たら、すごく安く済ませよう
to use the sun
太陽を利用する
At that time there was a second process
そのとき、第二のプロセスがありました
Come out and build a big project to do these things
出てきて、これらのことを行うための大規模なプロジェクトを構築してください
produce it
それを生産します
I don't expect it to be built any time soon
すぐに建てられるとは思えない
But it's worth sitting here and thinking about it
しかし、ここに座って考えてみる価値はある
Especially the Academia Sinica should have a lot of energy to do this
特に中央研究院はこれに多大なエネルギーを注ぐ必要がある
Before doing this, we need to know a lot of things
これを行う前に、多くのことを知る必要があります
because it is a design
それはデザインだから
The principle of design What is the design principle of bionics
設計原理 バイオニクスの設計原理とは
we need to understand it
私たちはそれを理解する必要があります
we don't just look at it
私たちはただそれを見るだけではありません
Sometimes you look at its appearance for a long time
その姿をずっと眺めていることもある
I really don't know what it does
本当に何をするのか分かりません
Like the fine algae just mentioned
先ほどの細かい藻類のように
you see it looks beautiful
ご覧のとおり、美しく見えます
but don't know what it does
でもそれが何をするのか分からない
Principles of Design
設計の原則
In addition, I am afraid that not all of them are self-installed.
また、残念ながらすべてが自己インストールできるわけではありません。
Creatures are all self-installed
クリーチャーはすべて自己インストールされます
Self-loading from the bottom up
下から上への自動読み込み
We may also have to go from top to bottom
上から下まで進む必要があるかもしれません
some designs
いくつかのデザイン
these combined
これらを組み合わせた
Of course these things are cross-cutting
もちろん、これらのことは横断的なものです
chemistry physics biology
化学物理生物学
Co-layer
共層
the last one
最後のもの
Combination across domains
ドメイン間の組み合わせ
such a thing
そんなこと
i think it's
それだと思います
an idea i'd love
私が気に入ったアイデア
family language propaganda
家族の言語によるプロパガンダ
convey
取り次ぐ
The last word is about the students
最後は生徒たちについてです
how did you do it
どうやってやったの？
to do these interdisciplinary learning
こうした学際的な学習を行うために
some things i'm doing now
私が今やっていることのいくつか
do this
これを行う
middle school textbook
中学校の教科書
design
設計
my Ministry of Education said
私の文部省はこう言いました
Although my Ministry of Education does not sell books
私の文科省は本を売っていませんが、
But they are developing teaching materials
しかし、彼らは教材を開発中です
never done well
決してうまくできなかった
I think it is not put this
これは置いてないと思います
A good combination of life technology and natural science
ライフテクノロジーと自然科学の上手な組み合わせ
You now know that there is nature in the country
この国には自然があることがわかりました
and living technology
そして生きたテクノロジー
Then everyone recognizes life technology
そうすれば誰もが認めるライフテクノロジー
public welfare
厚生
nature is physics
自然は物理学です
physical chemistry lesson by lesson
物理化学の授業ごとに
In fact, Guo Zhongyou did the same thing.
実際、郭仲佑も同じことをしました。
just deal with the mage
魔術師とだけ対処してください
but
しかし
You have to be the last to enter the battle
あなたは最後に戦闘に参加する必要があります
The basic principles of physical chemistry biological
物理化学の基本原理
and how did he design a thing
そして彼はどのようにして物をデザインしたのでしょうか
His design in a living organism is
生物における彼のデザインは、
very complicated very complicated
非常に複雑 非常に複雑
we have some design ideas
いくつかのデザインアイデアがあります
in student education
学生教育において
I think it's quite necessary
かなり必要だと思います
if it can be integrated
統合できれば
learn early
早く学ぶ
New Year's Eve Music Learning
大晦日の音楽学習
and then do this comparison
そしてこの比較をしてください
The so-called integrative biology
所謂 integrative biology
Integrative Biology Words
統合生物学の言葉
Finally a wonderful infrastructure
ついに素晴らしいインフラが完成しました
Fantastic applications may develop
素晴らしいアプリケーションが開発されるかもしれません
ok i will stop here today
はい、今日はここで終わります
Finally, thank you Nie Ting
最後に、ニー・ティンさん、ありがとう
and many of my collaborators
そして私の多くの協力者たち
and my students
そして私の生徒たち
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thanks
ありがとう
There's still a lot of time
まだ時間はたくさんある
If you want to ask a certain teacher
ある先生に聞きたいときは
He's at Nanotech and this
彼はナノテックにいて、これ
this benefit
この特典
concept words
概念の言葉
let's open the discussion first
まずディスカッションを開いてみましょう
ask a professor
教授に聞く
About your nano-bionic materials
ナノバイオニクス材料について
Is it for our human body
それは私たち人間の体のためですか？
suffering from bone
骨に苦しんでいる
What do patients with this disease have
この病気の患者は何を抱えているのか
What are the benefits?
メリットは何ですか?
Thanks
ありがとう
i'm not a doctor
私は医者ではありません
So I'm afraid I can't say
だから言えないのが怖い
directly to a patient
患者に直接
I can only talk about it from the point of view of material concept
マテリアルコンセプトの観点からしか語れない
If he wants to be a material senior
彼が物質的な先輩になりたいのなら
The last thing he might have done was an artificial skeleton
彼が最後にやったのは人工骨格だったかもしれない
we are all now
私たちは今全員です
with artificial bones
人工骨付き
material artificial bone
材質人工骨
Mainly too metal and metal
主にタイメタルとメタル
But one day maybe we can emulate it a little better
でもいつか、もう少しうまくエミュレートできるかもしれない
it is relatively light
比較的軽いです
and from time to time technology
そして時々テクノロジー
Maybe it's something like bones with zero calcium acid and slowly do it
たぶんそれはカルシウム酸ゼロの骨のようなもので、ゆっくりとそれを行います
But it's still far away
でもまだ遠いよ
At present, Taihe gold is used to make artificial bones
現在、太和金は人工骨の製造に使用されています。
But the surface treatment is to prevent kidney
しかし、表面処理は腎臓を防ぐためのものです
make it biocompatible
生体適合性を持たせる
If this is to that extent
そこまでなら
Materials used
使用材料
if not to that point
そこまでじゃないなら
Of course you should eat more calcium
もちろんカルシウムもたくさん摂ったほうがいいですよ
eat more vitamins
もっとビタミンを食べる
dorsese sun
多塞塞太陽
This is quite necessary
これはかなり必要です
we see the same creatures
私たちは同じ生き​​物を見ます
words like bones
骨のような言葉
It can grow as big as Konglong
コンロンと同じくらい大きくなることもあります
It can be as small as a mouse bone
ネズミの骨ほど小さいものもあります
you see that algae now
今その藻が見えますね
it has a very complex structure
非常に複雑な構造をしています
Then there's no way we'll find that
それではそれを見つける方法はありません
Like that factor that makes the bones grow and shrink
骨が伸びたり縮んだりする要素のように
Scale up that slender structure
その細長い構造をスケールアップ
to the size we want to apply
適用したいサイズに合わせて
if i knew how the lab did it
研究室がどうやってやったのか知っていたら
Maybe it can, but the creature has a certain size
おそらく可能ですが、生き物にはある程度のサイズがあります
Slender is a single celled organism
細長いものは単細胞生物です
Its creatures are born so small
その生き物はとても小さく生まれます
micron, but human words are far, far away from this
ミクロンですが、人間の言葉はこれからはるかに遠いです
to make such a good structure
こんなに良い構造を作るには
I at least admit I don't know how to make it up
少なくとも、それを補う方法がわからないことは認めます
We have to make a big decision
私たちは大きな決断をしなければなりません
it's a mess it has holes
穴だらけでめちゃくちゃだ
but the shape is ugly
しかし形は醜い
No it's not easy to control it's that big
いいえ、制御するのは簡単ではありません、とても大きいです
Our control is from small to high
私たちのコントロールは小さいものから高いものまで
The harder it is to control, most people think that
コントロールが難しいほど、ほとんどの人は次のように考えています。
big good control no
大きな良いコントロールなし
Because if it wants to be self-assertive, use chemistry to let it be self-assertive
自己主張したいなら化学を使って自己主張させればいいから
It's getting harder and harder to control
コントロールするのがますます難しくなっている
i mean
つまり
Konglong like the same bone
コンロンは同じ骨のようです
it can grow so big
とても大きく成長することができます
The mouse has such a small bone
ネズミの骨はとても小さい
between them to control it
それらの間でそれを制御するために
Factors that can grow so big
大きく成長する要因
or long so small factor
または長い間非常に小さな要素
There should be a mechanism
仕組みがあるはずだ
It must have a genetic component
遺伝的要素があるに違いない
there is a mechanism
仕組みがある
That mechanism can be found
その仕組みがわかる
and then apply it to something else
そしてそれを他のものに適用する
words in a way
ある意味言葉
We genetically modify
私たちは遺伝子組み換えを行っています
Can make a bigger animal benefit
より大きな動物利益をもたらすことができる
But this is still somewhat limited
しかし、これはまだある程度制限されています
perhaps
多分
But the control of our creatures
しかし、私たちの生き物のコントロールは、
We don't do it casually, do we?
何気なくやっているわけではないですよね？
There is also this ethical issue
こういう倫理的な問題もあるし
these questions
これらの質問
But if we talk about experimental flow synthesis
ただし、実験的なストリーム合成の場合は、
there is no way
道はない
Because this is what I just said
これは私が今言ったことだから
I don't know what you mean by creature control
クリーチャーコントロールって何のことを言っているのか分かりませんが、
Biocontrol for genetic modification
遺伝子組み換えのための生物的制御
yes to some extent
はい、ある程度は
have
もつ
Even if it is good, I just want to ask
それでいいから聞いてみたい
I just saw it in a header
ヘッダーで見ました
There is a picture about that ultraviolet light
その紫外線についての写真があります
its effect on the surface properties of the object
物体の表面特性に対する影響
like the surface of carbon dioxide
二酸化炭素の表面のように
Then it should be in that
それならその中にあるはずです
Changes in water clarity and water transport
水の透明度と水の輸送の変化
it is a molecule above
それは上の分子です
That molecule deforms when it shines light on it
その分子は光を当てると変形します
That head is a molecule of oil
その頭は油の分子です
it stands up and feels like oil
立ち上がって油のような感触
and then give it the overdrive result
そしてオーバードライブの結果を与えます
It's more oily and more watery
油っぽいし水っぽいし
But if you turn on the power
でも電源を入れると
Its molecular deformation will come down like this
分子変形はこうやって降りてきます
Exposed is another form of molecule
別の形態の分子が露出しています
it can do this
それはこれができます
So this charge
それでこの料金は
In addition, pH control is also available
さらにpHコントロールも可能
it can control a surface
表面をコントロールできる
To change its water-clearing and water-transmitting properties
透水性と透水性を変えるには
Hello, Mr. Mono, I just want to ask for advice
こんにちは、モノ先生、アドバイスが聞きたいのですが
Just like you do with the refugee materials
難民の物資を扱うのと同じように
Like controlling the PH value
PH値をコントロールするのと同じように
Would it make a difference that
それは違いを生むだろうか
The body size is different like this
本体サイズはこんな感じで違います
That is, relatively speaking, the pH value is important for living things.
つまり、相対的に言えば、生物にとって pH 値は重要です。
Will it affect him?
それは彼に影響を及ぼしますか？
Then another question is to say
それから、もう一つの質問はこう言うことです
If you are making refugee material
難民素材を作っている場合
Like now maybe doing some chemical batteries like this
今は化学電池をやっているかもしれない
If it is really applied to the human body
本当に人体に応用されたら
during its manufacture
製造中に
like some refugee particles would say
一部の難民粒子が言うように
some powder layers during the manufacturing process
製造工程中の一部の粉末層
cause harm to a person
人に危害を加える
Even when it is really applied to the human body
実際に人体に応用する場合でも
can't be ruled out
除外することはできません
Let’s talk about refugees’ impact on the human body
難民が人体に与える影響について話しましょう
the bad words
悪い言葉
I really don't know a lot of things now
今は本当に知らないことがたくさんある
You just don't want to eat indiscriminately.
ただ無差別に食べたくないだけです。
Then what I'm talking about doesn't apply to the human body.
それでは、私が話していることは人体には当てはまりません。
i don't have today
今日はありません
I'm not talking about medicine tomorrow
明日の薬の話ではない
what you'll swallow when you make the wrong food
間違った食べ物を作ったら何を飲み込むか
all on one device
すべてを 1 つのデバイス上で
that should be fine
それでいいはずです
we don't just try
私たちはただ努力するだけではありません
It's a battery, right?
バッテリーですよね？
this part
この部分
still good
まだいい
But it's true that biological control is on the way
しかし、生物学的制御が進行中であることは事実です
Bi our laboratory control is much higher
私たちの研究室の管理ははるかに高度です
Our laboratory can change the pH arbitrarily
私たちの研究室はpHを任意に変えることができます
What is the difference in the configuration of the material made by different pH
pHの違いによる物質の構造の違いは何ですか
Biology doesn't have that many options
生物学には選択肢がそれほど多くない
Its PH is around seven o'clock
PHは7時頃です
but it can do so many things
しかし、それは非常に多くのことができます
it can still be controlled to
まだ制御できる
Many chemical reactions if in neutral
中性であれば多くの化学反応が起こります
hard to do can't do it
難しいことはできない
but it has no valid number
しかし有効な番号がありません
it does not catalyze
それは触媒作用をしません
So the reaction math speeds up
したがって、反応計算が高速化されます
so
それで
Why when the pH value is lower
pH値が低いとなぜ
Its crystallization period is smaller and more irregular
結晶化周期はより小さく、より不規則です
Not necessarily not necessarily
必ずしもではない 必ずしもではない
I don't know you want to take a material not necessarily
必ずしも資料を取りたいとは限りません
what is not necessarily
必ずしもそうではないもの
uncertain
不確かな
Where is MX
MXはどこですか
that's not necessarily
それは必ずしもそうではありません
That's what we want to control
それが私たちがコントロールしたいことです
Tell me about one of my articles
私の記事について教えてください
i know what you're going to say
あなたが何を言おうとしているのか分かります
The nano hole
ナノホール
Dioxide series material
二酸化物系材質
Then P is also empty
すると P も空になります
its big horns right
大きな角がありますよね
yes
はい
But there are other variations
しかし、他にもバリエーションがあります
Or if you change the temperature and change the gas
あるいは温度を変えたり、ガスを変えたりすると
it's not the same
それは同じではありません
I can't go into details about this.
これについては詳しく説明できません。
that's right
それは正しい
I probably know about your temperature problem
あなたの体温の問題についてはおそらく知っています
maybe ask again
もう一度聞いてみるかもしれない
behind this side
こちら側の後ろに
Beyond the level of this puzzling invention
この不可解な発明のレベルを超えて
a lot of this hygiene
この衛生状態の多くは
All at the level of difficulty invented
すべては発明された難易度レベルで
right
右
especially sick
特に病気
it's a virus
それはウイルスです
it seems
そうみたいです
We call it this breeding
私たちはこれを繁殖と呼んでいます
its energy
そのエネルギー
out of its control
制御不能になった
These problems are solved
これらの問題は解決されます
Then we are confused about the material
それから、素材で迷ってしまいます
Have you learned much about this?
これについて多くのことを学びましたか?
Learn from viruses
ウイルスから学ぶ
virus it's
ウイルスだよ
may say these things
こういうことを言うかもしれない
its handed over to technology
それはテクノロジーに引き継がれました
it's not interested in itself
それ自体に興味がない
Process Metabolism doesn't do these things
プロセス代謝はこれらのことを行いません
that's a good idea
それは良いアイデアです
Someday I will make a nano show
いつかナノショーを作ります
to invade a cell
細胞に侵入する
Let the cells do what I want
細胞に私が望むようにさせてください
maybe one day
いつの日にか
But this requires a thorough understanding of life
しかし、これには人生についての徹底的な理解が必要です
I think we're pretty good at this
私たちはこれに関してはかなり上手だと思います
because you're here to be you
あなたはあなたになるためにここにいるから
I mentioned this self-installation
この自己インストールについて言及しました
Safe assembly
安全な組み立て
What is our mechanism for Safe assembly?
安全に組み立てるための仕組みとは何ですか?
simple
単純
If, for example, a surface mono layer
たとえば、表面単層の場合
Safe assembly
安全な組み立て
like the outside world
外の世界のように
what does professor tao yutai do
タオ・ユタイ教授は何をしていますか
that understands quite
それはよくわかります
that is very restricted
それは非常に制限されています
very limited
非常に限られた
But if a three-dimensional structure
しかし、三次元構造であれば、
Then, if you take the level
次に、レベルを取ると、
really know very little
本当にほとんど知らない
so many things are
とてもたくさんのことが
just wear L
Lだけ着てください
have to try more
もっと試してみなければなりません
But there will be some hints and some conjectures
しかし、いくつかのヒントといくつかの推測があるでしょう
but no good theory
でも良い理論はない
you do those things
あなたはそれらのことをします
For mentioning this imitative word
この擬態語について言及したことで
generally speaking
一般的に言えば
is doing the most on the fly
最も多くのことをその場で行っています
also compare the best
最高のものとの比較も
that this
これは
words in chemistry
化学の言葉
I feel like I did it late
遅くまでやった気がする
How far are you doing now?
今どこまでやってるの？
really
本当
It's a lot worse
それははるかに悪いです
relatively late start
比較的遅いスタート
Because this series of Nano moves it is very complicated
この一連のNanoの動きは非常に複雑なので、
It first has a joint structure
まずジョイント構造があります
Then it will be difficult for you to get out
そうなると抜け出すのが難しくなる
The second is like schooling out something like this
2つ目は、このようなことを教育するようなものです
it is very finely conditioned
とてもきれいに整備されています
you don't look at it this center
このセンターでは見ていません
the water pipe
水道管
Everything around will be affected
周りのものすべてが影響を受けます
It is difficult for us to imitate it completely
完全に真似するのは難しい
So the so-called bionics sometimes
それで、いわゆるバイオニクスは時々
That is to say, it is inspired to do this
これは、それに触発されてこれを行うことを意味します
behind that
その後ろに
that
それか
if the creature size
生き物のサイズなら
Now some genetic engineering
さて、遺伝子工学について
Or use artificial hormones
あるいは人工ホルモンを使用する
actually allows fish to grow much faster or triple in size
実際、魚ははるかに速く成長したり、サイズが3倍になったりする可能性があります
someone did it
誰かがやった
Like Shamon now with genetic engineering
遺伝子工学を使った今のシャモンみたいに
But it seems that I have just been allowed to work
でも、やっと仕事が許されたみたいです
So how about being listed in that European country?
では、そのヨーロッパの国に上場されるのはどうでしょうか？
If you have a virus
ウイルスに感染している場合
Many people now use genetically modified viruses
現在、多くの人が遺伝子組み換えウイルスを使用しています
So this virus can help you make protein
つまり、このウイルスはタンパク質の生成を助けることができるのです
Or the tool of Ganggene delivery
またはGanggene配信のツール
This machine does a lot
この機械はいろいろなことができる
But this is not completely artificial like yours.
しかし、これはあなたのもののように完全に人工的なものではありません。
is this genetic modification
これは遺伝子組み換えですか
But here comes a problem
しかし、ここで問題が発生します
Ask Professor Mao
マオ先生に聞く
I just mentioned that it's useful
便利だと言っただけです
The method of life is afraid of substances to replace this SOD
このSODに代わる物質を恐れる生き方
So it can be used as a valid number
したがって、有効な数値として使用できます
Now in terms of reproductive energy
今回は「生殖エネルギー」について
Many people use Sanway efficacious numbers
多くの人がサンウェイの有効な番号を使用しています
The Sanway effect is very difficult to produce
サンウェイ効果を生み出すのは非常に難しい
then the wood is very hard
それから木はとても硬いです
very difficult to digest
消化するのが非常に難しい
Then you see, it means using your inexplicable technology
そうすると、それはあなたの不可解なテクノロジーを使用することを意味します
Replacing reproductive energy in the future
将来の生殖エネルギーの代替
to the possibility of digesting wood into energy
木材を消化してエネルギーに変える可能性へ
How high is the new chance
新しいチャンスはどのくらいですか
The bionic one now
今ではバイオニックなもの
efficacies to decompose that
それを分解する効能
made of fiber
繊維でできた
Can still make considerable progress
まだかなりの進歩を遂げる可能性があります
But the hardest is the wooden number
でも一番難しいのは木の数字です
that part of the wooden number
木の数字のその部分
really difficult
本当に難しい
let me see
そうねぇ
I can't imitate that effect
その効果は真似できない
natural efficiency
自然な効率
You can decompose that part of the wooden number
木の数字のその部分を分解できます
Do you know what I mean
分かりますか
Fiber count is relatively easy is some
繊維数は比較的簡単ですが、
Lie together and cut that middle off
一緒に寝て、真ん中を切り取ってください
But woody numbers are more complicated
しかし、木の数字はもっと複雑です
a natural wood
天然木
it's very complicated inside
内部は非常に複雑です
we also
私達も
There is no way to deal with it all
全てに対処する方法はない
but in progress
しかし進行中です
so
それで
is there any problem
何か問題ある
or
また
This because it does not specify
明記してないからこうなる
just click
クリックするだけです
press the green one
緑色のものを押してください
good
良い
Because I think bionic words
バイオニックワードだと思うから
just like nature fucks
まるで自然が性交するかのように
sometimes not very strong
時々あまり強くない
why
なぜ
Because nature's requirements are different from our requirements
自然の要求は私たちの要求とは異なるため
no the same
いいえ同じです
for example
例えば
In Taiwan we all like to make money first
台湾では誰もがまずお金を稼ぐことを好みます
the words of nature
自然の言葉
I guess the idea of ​​making money isn't enough
お金を稼ぐという考えだけでは十分ではないと思います
it may be survival first
まずは生き残ることかもしれない
So play today like a natural gymnastics
だから今日は自然な体操のように遊んでください
I think sometimes it's not very strong
あまり強くない場合もあると思います
Should I say yes
はいと言ったほうがいいでしょうか
In addition to operating
運営に加えて、
You are like these rises of nature
あなたは自然の隆起のようなものです
inspiration
インスピレーション
yeah i just mentioned
はい、先ほど言いました
In fact, many jobs are like this now
実際、今は多くの仕事がそうなっている
otherwise
さもないと
We are now singing the high profile of this innovation
私たちは今、このイノベーションの注目度の高さを歌っています。
simply impossible
単純に不可能
Yes, from this body to
そう、この身体から
in my speech today
今日の私のスピーチの中で
I did not put the Bio-Memetic
バイオミームは入れてない
Let me distinguish between these two Inspires
この 2 つの Inspire を区別させてください
maybe i should make it next time
次回は作ろうかな
better distinction
より良い区別
In fact many jobs are Bio-Inspired
実際、多くの仕事はバイオからインスピレーションを得たものです
no
いいえ
imitated but by his natural
模倣されたが、彼の自然によるもの
to spark your imagination
あなたの想像力を刺激するために
Many jobs are of the form
多くの仕事は次のような形式です
i think this is
これだと思います
He should be distinguished
彼は区別されるべきだ
Because I heard stuff stuff
いろいろ聞いたので
materials of nature
天然素材
especially hard materials
特に硬い素材
it has few basic elements
基本的な要素はほとんどありません
It is all structured
それはすべて構造化されています
it is structured
それは構造化されています
the technology of our characters
私たちのキャラクターのテクノロジー
It's just a little bit different
それは少しだけ違います
on the contrary
相反
We say that the basic elements are many
基本的な要素はたくさんあると言いますが、
The middle of the result
結果の真ん中
The so-called structured
所谓structured
not too much
多すぎない程度に
But workers we seem
しかし、私たちは労働者のように見えます
less natural materials
天然素材が少ない
Its optimization is very good
最適化は非常に優れています
Yes, this understanding is very
はい、この理解は非常に良いです
Nature has dozens of years
自然には何十年もある
we don't have that long
そんなに長くはない
they have thirty one years
彼らには31年あります
progress slowly
ゆっくりと進む
to evolve him
彼を進化させるために
right
右
we don't have that long
そんなに長くはない
so
それで
Especially since I just said a lot
特にさっき色々言ったので
is playing now
今遊んでいます
Existing theme
既存のテーマ
so we are still learning
だから私たちはまだ学んでいる途中です
we are really far behind
私たちは本当に遅れています
talk to nature
自然と話す
still a lot worse
まだはるかに悪い
So we have to learn from nature
だから私たちは自然から学ばなければなりません
ok thanks Kohman
わかりました、ありがとうコーマン
is there any problem
何か問題ある
well, talk about nothing
まあ、何も話さないで
we'll be a drummer later
私たちは後でドラマーになります
Thank you Professor Nakahara
中原先生、ありがとうございました
Jin Xia's speech
ジン・シア氏のスピーチ
Thank you for your participation
ご参加ありがとうございます
Thanks
ありがとう